<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The internet place for Alice Bartlett</title>
    <description>The website of Alice Bartlett. Front-end developer and internet person.</description>
    <link>https://alicebartlett.co.uk/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://alicebartlett.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 19:44:56 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 19:44:56 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 46: Tepid nonsense</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the muddle of evening driving we did last week I listened to some good podcasts. One was &lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/episode/built-on-sand/&quot;&gt;this episode of 99% Invisible about sand&lt;/a&gt;. Did you know that sand grains are a different shape if eroded by wind vs water? And the wind type is useless in creating concrete because it’s spherical. Did you know that each year we build 7 New York’s worth of buildings globally? Did you know that sand is a finite commodity and one day we’ll reach peak sand?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is also more Revisionist History which is my favourite podcast.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;That sound? Oh it’s just my teeth grinding as more lukewarm responses about that man’s bad opinion about what good engineers look like flutter across my timeline. Partly this is because twitter keeps promoting tweets other people have favourited to me, and some of you do favourite some very tepid nonsense.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve given up meat. So far it’s fine at home - I stopped preparing meat based meals at home in January and it was pretty easy. At work though, ugh, it sucks. I think I’ll be able to keep it up, but it does require the same kind of will power as keeping secrets and not eating lots of cake, and um. I’m not very good at either of those in fact I would go so far as to say I am actually bad at both of those.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On Thursday I was 29 minutes late to a 30 minute meeting because I was eating biscuits and gossiping. I had actually forgotten the meeting entirely but because it was important and I really should have been there I went for the last one minute to see if there were any actions. 😳&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Did I tell you that I deleted my Facebook profile? Yes I did that.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Today we went to the (re)opening of Beckenham Place Park. It’s so nice. It used to be a council funded golf course but nobody every used it so the council have converted it into a massive park complete with a swimming pond!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;💥&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-46</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-46</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 45: One day this will be an otter 🦦</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This week we went to Dorset with my parents. I found a cuttlefish bone on the beach. Alice Malia has a good instagram line in “sea treasures” which I always like looking at. You can’t see them though because her account is private and you’re not lucky enough to be her friend.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The house we stayed in had a PS4 with Minecraft on it so Lachie and I played a lot of that.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The house we stayed in also had a lot of silverfish, one of which I saw scuttle into my laptop fan vent. I haven’t seen it come out yet 😱&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Margaritas are good aren’t they.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I can hear my toddler giggling and saying “oh no!!!” as her daddy swings her around and tickles her.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There’s isn’t currently an emoji for the face Lachie and I do when E does something excessively cute. It’s an extreme scrunching up of the eyes and nose and a pursing of the lips. We’ve got an otter emoji now (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/snootgirl/status/1093215152579710976&quot;&gt;one day this will be an otter 🦦&lt;/a&gt;). I think the unicode consortium should tackle this next.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;E absolutely loves books (nerd). “Oh No, GEORGE!” is the best one as it gives her many opportunities to say “Oh no GEORGE!”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My house probably has silverfish now doesn’t it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jen’s written &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/ft-product-technology/documentation-day-how-the-ft-com-team-improved-our-documentation-to-95-usefulness-in-7-hours-b73d1a7e6f30&quot;&gt;a thing&lt;/a&gt; about how we had a documentation day. I haven’t read it yet because I’ve been on holiday, but I helped a tiny bit with the draft. Can we talk about how much better people at work have gotten about writing about the things they’ve done on the work blog? It’s like, actually good now? Well done people at work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;🍐&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-45</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-45</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 44: White Frag</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Good morning.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Big week people. &lt;em&gt;Big week&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The FT’s Chief Commercial Officer spent four days with our team to learn about how Product and Technology works. On Monday he shadowed the team on support duty for a bit, triaging and fixing bugs, came to a planning meeting, and we taught him some conversational topics for impressing his computery friends - Tabs vs Spaces, “bike shedding” and “rubber ducking”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We shipped the engineering progression beta! I knew this next bit was going to be a slog. The first big - discovery, ideas, &lt;em&gt;anything is possible&lt;/em&gt; always goes quickly with energy and enthusiasm. But getting from alpha to beta involved the less glamorous labour of listening to people, understanding them and improving based on their feedback. I wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/ft-product-technology/career-progression-framework-update-a2eb23115422&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; about getting from alpha to beta. It’s not very interesting but, as we all know, PUBLISH DON’T SEND.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The screening of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=45ey4jgoxeU&quot;&gt;White Frag&lt;/a&gt; as I have come to call it internally was great. We managed to exceed the expected turnout and had to order in more snacks. We did this largely by asking (white) people 1:1 “are you coming to the screening later? - it’s a very good film”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some reflections on watching it for the fourth time:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Watching this film at work was absolutely excruciating. Though I had seen the lecture three times already, seeing it sat next to white colleagues that I knew had not considered their own racism in this way, folks who are more important than me, older, wiser, busier, more stressed. Seeing them watch Robin point out and dissect their white fragility and how it was protecting them from seeing or thinking about racism was unbearably awkward.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It was also differently excruciating, and far worse, watching it with my colleagues of colour. Seeing them listen to Robin D’Angelo say things like “I believe there is something profoundly anti-black in our society. Nothing annoys white people more than thinking black people got something over on them that they didn’t deserve” made me feel like I might actually cry. I felt the weight of what I had organised - I had convinced a group of people of colour to come to a room and listen to the many ways in which they were at a disadvantage. Things they already knew and had been dealing with all their lives. These feelings are mine to sit with, I’m not bringing them up because I want any kind of reassurance from anybody. I think they’re useful because they give me a thing to improve on. I should have been direct about checking with my colleagues (who were mostly from the Embrace committee, with whom I had organised the event) that they knew the contents of the lecture ahead of time and were still interested in attending.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;After the event I spoke to a few people, the white people were wide eyed, still rolling the lecture around in their heads, turning it over. The people who had seen it before told me on second watching they had gotten more out of  it. It’s very dense so there’s a lot to miss the first time. I heard from some people of colour that they also found the lecture useful as it had given them a language to codify things they knew but hadn’t worked out how to say.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;For me, the takeaways remain similar to what &lt;a href=&quot;https://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-31&quot;&gt;I wrote about before&lt;/a&gt;: this lecture has given me the language to talk about my own racism and white fragility. I’m not afraid of “saying something racist” anymore because I know that fear is stopping me from acting to combat racism. I know that the pro-move is (as with everything) learning how to apologise, repair, and not repeat mistakes.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I don’t waste time feeling guilty about my white privilege because that guilt isn’t doing anything unless I convert it into action. I also don’t tell people I feel bad, because that just puts some emotional labour on them to comfort me which is the absolute opposite of what I want to do.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;After I watched the lecture the first time, something I did think about was the fact that Robin D’Angelo is white. Would that lecture have landed with me if she had been a woman of colour? Almost certainly not. I might not even have heard about it. Another thing I considered is the difference between the United States’s history and that of Great Britain. I resolved to address these issues by learning about the UK’s racial history, and reading it as told by people of colour. It took next to zero effort to find &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.audible.co.uk/pd/Why-Im-No-Longer-Talking-to-White-People-About-Race-Audiobook/B06XGLP7NP?source_code=M2M14DFT1BkSH082015011R&amp;amp;ds_rl=1235779&quot;&gt;Reni Eddo-Lodge’s book “Why I am no longer talking to white people about race”&lt;/a&gt; and this &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/user-957591628/32-akala-race-and-class-in-the-ruins-of-empire&quot;&gt;Akala interview with James O’Brien&lt;/a&gt;. Both of these are really useful follow ups to D’Angelo’s lecture, and cover the history of race in Britain (spoiler - it’s also bad)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;😓&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-44-1</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-44-1</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 43: Noodle</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scorchio! 🌞&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I ran a documentation day at work this week. Probably the best thing about it was getting the team together to work on something as a group. Everybody paired up to tackle one thing but we all sat near each other, shared snacks and tips. It was really fun, and our runbooks are in much better shape because of it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Because I love making things and finding excuses to make things, I made some trophies for the teams that ended up with the best runbook. It’s difficult to judge how good a runbook is, so I didn’t want to make the prizes good/expensive because it would be difficult to award them completely fairly. I had to noodle around a bit with ideas before I realised these trophies should be characterful books holding pencils that detached so people could bin the trophy but use the pencil. Here is a photo.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/trophies.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Trophies&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m organising a screening of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=45ey4jgoxeU&quot;&gt;this lecture about “white fragility”&lt;/a&gt; with BAME network at work. I’m pretty excited about it, I hope a lot of my white colleagues come along, but who knows what will happen to be honest.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;🌵&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-43</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-43</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 42: Sweet pea</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Day late with the weaknotes this week, I was a bit busy yesterday.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This week I went to a conference that the same number of women speaking as there were men named Patrick. Many of the conference talks were very good and I was glad I went, but yeah. Not a good line up.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It feels bad when you care about doing something difficult well but then still manage to mess it up. Try not to dwell on how bad it feels, or make excuses about how you tried. None of those feelings or excuses are helping you improve the thing you care about.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am trying to show E how to smell things, but she thinks I am blowing on them. It is very good to see her gently take a sweet pea, bring it up to her nose and softly, so softly, blow on it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;👪&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-42</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-42</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 41: Biggleywinks</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shout out to whoever cleared all the tampons out of the work tampon club. I can only assume you really needed 20 tampons in one go, but are planning on replacing them shortly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am the top Google result for “hoisted by Jean-luc Picard” &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; “chill yoghurt babe&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;”, maybe the algorithms aren’t actually bad.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Boris Johnson is going to be our prime minister. I have made my piece with it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hi I listen to audiobooks now. I had been not doing that because it felt like not proper reading. But then I was like “Alice you loser, you’re cheating yourself out of many great ideas because your have inhaled some bollocks about reading with your eyes being the only legitimate form of consuming books. Get a grip.” So now I listen to audio books. I’m about half way through “Why I’m no longer talking to white people about race” by Reni Eddo-Lodge which is good and interesting so far.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have been making models today with SuperSculpey. It’s good, I think I might be doing a good thing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Everyone have a little think about biggleywinks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;☠️&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Credit to &lt;a href=&quot;https://chee.snoot.club/&quot;&gt;Chee&lt;/a&gt; for discovering this &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-41</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-41</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 40: Strongly pro</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gilest.org/bwrss.html&quot;&gt;Giles has done a good thing&lt;/a&gt;. I’m strongly pro RSS so an RSS only photo feed - even for only a month - is very appealing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I feel very tired.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;That is all.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;🍤&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-40</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-40</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 39: Typing the right things fast</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I keep meaning to say something about &lt;a href=&quot;https://nordprojects.co/projects/littleprinters/&quot;&gt;the return of Little Printer&lt;/a&gt; but then forgetting. My main thought is that it’s really nice that they’ve revived the impact-y message style - I wrote the original code for that. It was nearly Christmas and Jack had had this idea for a new messaging style that he thought would be cool. I was supposed to be working on something else so after I’d finished the day’s work I started noodling around with it, trying to work out algorithmically how to get the word sizing right, learning about leading and kerning. It was incredibly fun and when I had finished I pushed a release live and sent a message to Jack’s little printer in his house in the new style. Something like “THIS LOOKS PRETTY GOOD I THINK”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The other Little Printer messaging memory I have is the time somebody down the pub sent “HELLO YOU C**T”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to Matt Jones’ little printer in the middle of the night. I can’t remember whose friend that was, but I don’t think Matt found it very funny. After that we put some configuration in to stop people messaging you in the middle of the night. A swear filter might also have been a good idea, but these are the kinds of things you only think of after you have kids.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is making me want to go find my Little Printer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I just bought &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.jp/dp/4579116879/ref=pe_492632_159100282_TE_item&quot;&gt;Yumiko Higuchi’s new book of embroidery&lt;/a&gt; from Amazon Japan. I know there will be an english language translation of it eventually bit I absolutely cannot wait for that. I know enough embroidery to not need the instructions. Probably.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://russelldavies.typepad.com/planning/2019/05/age-and-trying-not-to.html&quot;&gt;Russell did a good blog post about how you can’t market to old people&lt;/a&gt; and it really Made Me Think.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve done a new layout style for my sewing posts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve written that talk abstract I was procrastinating from. If anyone wants a talk about Git HMU.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being a good developer is as much about typing the right things fast as it is about helping others to type the right things fast.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thanks for the shout out &lt;a href=&quot;https://tomarmitage.com/2019/05/31/week-334/&quot;&gt;Tom&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This week’s word is kerning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This week’s emoji is 😯&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I have starred this out because I &lt;em&gt;try&lt;/em&gt; not to swear in my weaknotes. Please email me for the unasterisked version of this correspondence. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-39</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-39</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 38: This week&#39;s least popular word is &#39;automating&#39;</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Uh, so satisfying being able to type &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;make-week&lt;/code&gt; and just know that my very clever bash script will calculate the date of next Saturday and populate the front matter for my weaknotes. This has given me an idea for automating my post titles too… [some typing later] … OK well if I want to know the least popular word in every weaknote was I’ve now got a script for that… I could write a commit hook that creates the title every time I commit the weaknote. Would that be good? They’d probably be a bit rubbish. Can you tell I’m procrastinating from writing a conference talk?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What if I just wrote a commit hook at appended “This week’s least popular word was &lt;em&gt;whatever&lt;/em&gt;” to the end of the weaknote. Would that be fun. That might be fun. SHUT UP AND WRITE YOUR TALK ABSTRACT AB.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I went to the Alresford watercress festival last weekend. It was good - there were lots of dogs for E to look at and she was just incredibly happy to be there which was nice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In Alresford I also saw a set of quadruplets, so that’s something.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I just trod in a lot of dog poo. I was thinking about how dog poo is disgusting, but why is that? It’s made up of the same atoms that everything else is made up of, including me, so in some ways aren’t we all dog poo?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More typing happened and now I have some sentiment analysis which generates an emoji with the same sentiment. I’ve looked at the sentiment analysis algorithm and it is… not very smart.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This week’s emoji is 😱&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This week’s least popular word is “automating”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-38</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-38</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 37: (not a typo)</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We did a staycation this week, while E still went to nursery. We were meant to get some big DIY jobs done, but of the three Things To Do, all of them were delayed by something further across the Gantt chart.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I don’t normally listen to This American Life, but a friend pointed me to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thisamericanlife.org/674/get-a-spine/act-one-3&quot;&gt;this episode&lt;/a&gt; about Dan Harmon’s apology to Mengan Ganz, a writer he sexually harassed over two or three years and it is mind blowing. Dan Harmon was the creator and show runner for Community. Over the course of two years he harassed a woman on his staff that he was attracted to and then, when she rejected him, he belittled and humiliated her repeatedly. In the analysis of the apology, we hear about his previous attempts to apologise, which were rubbish, and we hear from the Megan about the impact being harassed had had on her. Listening to this made me feel slightly sick. I know a lot of men who do or have done varying shades of Dan Harmon. They should all listen to this or at the very least &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thisamericanlife.org/674/transcript&quot;&gt;read the transcript&lt;/a&gt;.
&amp;gt; “The trick is if you lie to yourself you can lie to everybody. It’s really easy. And so that’s what I continued to do, telling myself and anybody that threatened to confront me with it that if you thought what I was doing was creepy or flirty or unprofessional then it’s because you were the sexist. You were jealous. I was supporting this person. I’m a mentor, I’m a feminist.”
&amp;gt; “[After she rejected him] And that was probably the darkest of it all because I drank, I took pills, I crushed on her and resented her for not reciprocating it. And the entire time I was the one writing her pay checks and in control of whether she stayed or went, and whether she felt good about herself or not, and said horrible things. Just treated her cruelly, pointedly. Things that I would never, ever, ever have done if she had been male and if I had never had those feelings for her.”
&amp;gt; “And I never did it before and I will never do it again. But I certainly wouldn’t have been able to do it if I had any respect for women. On a fundamental level, I was thinking about them as different creatures.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This apology is really good because I think Dan Harmon is actually sorry about what he did and he took a big risk to improve the situation. In his apology he describes in a very clear and straightforward way what he did and why it was bad, he doesn’t make any excuses but he also doesn’t wallow in how sorry he is.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It should go without saying, but clearly doesn’t because I keep having to say this to people, the point of doing an apology well is to repair the harm you caused another person. It is to help them feel better and move on. If you don’t think you really caused any harm, and you are not actually sorry, then don’t apologise.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The other thing this made me think of is how annoying being a woman between the ages of 15 and 25 is. When I was younger it was basically impossible to tell which of my male peers were being nice to me because I was a chill yoghurt babe, and who was harbouring a nerd crush on me, which they would reveal to me at some point, in an awkward email, or a weird phone call, tainting every fun memory I had with them in the process. This is kind of the deal for a lot of young women, but it’s approximately 100 times more pronounced if you do a degree in Computer Science where the ratio of men to women is 80:3 (not a typo).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A talk I gave about Git has been circulated widely on twitter again which is giving me some warm feelings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am waiting for some babies to be born, it is an exciting time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>https://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-37</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-37</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
