<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The internet place for Alice Bartlett</title>
    <description>The website of Alice Bartlett. Front-end developer and internet person.</description>
    <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://alicebartlett.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 19:43:23 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 19:43:23 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 40:</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gilest.org/bwrss.html&quot;&gt;Giles has done a good thing&lt;/a&gt;. I’m strongly pro RSS so an RSS only photo feed - even for only a month - is very appealing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-40</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-40</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 39: Typing the right things fast</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I keep meaning to say something about &lt;a href=&quot;https://nordprojects.co/projects/littleprinters/&quot;&gt;the return of Little Printer&lt;/a&gt; but then forgetting. My main thought is that it’s really nice that they’ve revived the impact-y message style - I wrote the original code for that. It was nearly Christmas and Jack had had this idea for a new messaging style that he thought would be cool. I was supposed to be working on something else so after I’d finished the day’s work I started noodling around with it, trying to work out algorithmically how to get the word sizing right, learning about leading and kerning. It was incredibly fun and when I had finished I pushed a release live and sent a message to Jack’s little printer in his house in the new style. Something like “THIS LOOKS PRETTY GOOD I THINK”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The other Little Printer messaging memory I have is the time somebody down the pub sent “HELLO YOU C**T”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to Matt Jones’ little printer in the middle of the night. I can’t remember whose friend that was, but I don’t think Matt found it very funny. After that we put some configuration in to stop people messaging you in the middle of the night. A swear filter might also have been a good idea, but these are the kinds of things you only think of after you have kids.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is making me want to go find my Little Printer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I just bought &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.jp/dp/4579116879/ref=pe_492632_159100282_TE_item&quot;&gt;Yumiko Higuchi’s new book of embroidery&lt;/a&gt; from Amazon Japan. I know there will be an english language translation of it eventually bit I absolutely cannot wait for that. I know enough embroidery to not need the instructions. Probably.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://russelldavies.typepad.com/planning/2019/05/age-and-trying-not-to.html&quot;&gt;Russell did a good blog post about how you can’t market to old people&lt;/a&gt; and it really Made Me Think.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve done a new layout style for my sewing posts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve written that talk abstract I was procrastinating from. If anyone wants a talk about Git HMU.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being a good developer is as much about typing the right things fast as it is about helping others to type the right things fast.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thanks for the shout out &lt;a href=&quot;https://tomarmitage.com/2019/05/31/week-334/&quot;&gt;Tom&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This week’s word is kerning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This week’s emoji is 😯&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I have starred this out because I &lt;em&gt;try&lt;/em&gt; not to swear in my weaknotes. Please email me for the unasterisked version of this correspondence. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-39</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-39</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 38: This week&#39;s least popular word is &#39;automating&#39;</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Uh, so satisfying being able to type &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;make-week&lt;/code&gt; and just know that my very clever bash script will calculate the date of next Saturday and populate the front matter for my weaknotes. This has given me an idea for automating my post titles too… [some typing later] … OK well if I want to know the least popular word in every weaknote was I’ve now got a script for that… I could write a commit hook that creates the title every time I commit the weaknote. Would that be good? They’d probably be a bit rubbish. Can you tell I’m procrastinating from writing a conference talk?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What if I just wrote a commit hook at appended “This week’s least popular word was &lt;em&gt;whatever&lt;/em&gt;” to the end of the weaknote. Would that be fun. That might be fun. SHUT UP AND WRITE YOUR TALK ABSTRACT AB.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I went to the Alresford watercress festival last weekend. It was good - there were lots of dogs for E to look at and she was just incredibly happy to be there which was nice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In Alresford I also saw a set of quadruplets, so that’s something.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I just trod in a lot of dog poo. I was thinking about how dog poo is disgusting, but why is that? It’s made up of the same atoms that everything else is made up of, including me, so in some ways aren’t we all dog poo?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More typing happened and now I have some sentiment analysis which generates an emoji with the same sentiment. I’ve looked at the sentiment analysis algorithm and it is… not very smart.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This week’s emoji is 😱&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This week’s least popular word is “automating”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-38</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-38</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 37: (not a typo)</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We did a staycation this week, while E still went to nursery. We were meant to get some big DIY jobs done, but of the three Things To Do, all of them were delayed by something further across the Gantt chart.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I don’t normally listen to This American Life, but a friend pointed me to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thisamericanlife.org/674/get-a-spine/act-one-3&quot;&gt;this episode&lt;/a&gt; about Dan Harmon’s apology to Mengan Ganz, a writer he sexually harassed over two or three years and it is mind blowing. Dan Harmon was the creator and show runner for Community. Over the course of two years he harassed a woman on his staff that he was attracted to and then, when she rejected him, he belittled and humiliated her repeatedly. In the analysis of the apology, we hear about his previous attempts to apologise, which were rubbish, and we hear from the Megan about the impact being harassed had had on her. Listening to this made me feel slightly sick. I know a lot of men who do or have done varying shades of Dan Harmon. They should all listen to this or at the very least &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thisamericanlife.org/674/transcript&quot;&gt;read the transcript&lt;/a&gt;.
&amp;gt; “The trick is if you lie to yourself you can lie to everybody. It’s really easy. And so that’s what I continued to do, telling myself and anybody that threatened to confront me with it that if you thought what I was doing was creepy or flirty or unprofessional then it’s because you were the sexist. You were jealous. I was supporting this person. I’m a mentor, I’m a feminist.”
&amp;gt; “[After she rejected him] And that was probably the darkest of it all because I drank, I took pills, I crushed on her and resented her for not reciprocating it. And the entire time I was the one writing her pay checks and in control of whether she stayed or went, and whether she felt good about herself or not, and said horrible things. Just treated her cruelly, pointedly. Things that I would never, ever, ever have done if she had been male and if I had never had those feelings for her.”
&amp;gt; “And I never did it before and I will never do it again. But I certainly wouldn’t have been able to do it if I had any respect for women. On a fundamental level, I was thinking about them as different creatures.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This apology is really good because I think Dan Harmon is actually sorry about what he did and he took a big risk to improve the situation. In his apology he describes in a very clear and straightforward way what he did and why it was bad, he doesn’t make any excuses but he also doesn’t wallow in how sorry he is.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It should go without saying, but clearly doesn’t because I keep having to say this to people, the point of doing an apology well is to repair the harm you caused another person. It is to help them feel better and move on. If you don’t think you really caused any harm, and you are not actually sorry, then don’t apologise.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The other thing this made me think of is how annoying being a woman between the ages of 15 and 25 is. When I was younger it was basically impossible to tell which of my male peers were being nice to me because I was a chill yoghurt babe, and who was harbouring a nerd crush on me, which they would reveal to me at some point, in an awkward email, or a weird phone call, tainting every fun memory I had with them in the process. This is kind of the deal for a lot of young women, but it’s approximately 100 times more pronounced if you do a degree in Computer Science where the ratio of men to women is 80:3 (not a typo).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A talk I gave about Git has been circulated widely on twitter again which is giving me some warm feelings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am waiting for some babies to be born, it is an exciting time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-37</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-37</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tottorri cross Kalle</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After &lt;a href=&quot;https://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/bird-shirt&quot;&gt;my last Kalle shirt&lt;/a&gt; I knew I wanted to make another in &lt;a href=&quot;https://merchantandmills.com/store/cloth/tottorri-cross-black/&quot;&gt;this Japanese seersucker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This fabric is so delicious. That is all I have to say on this matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/sewing/tottori-kalle.1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Side view of my shirt&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/sewing/tottori-kalle.2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Back view of my shirt&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/sewing/tottori-kalle.3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Front view of my shirt&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/sewing/tottori-kalle.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Animated GIF of me in my shirt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/tottorri-cross-kalle</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/tottorri-cross-kalle</guid>
        
        
        <category>sewing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tottorri cross Bantam</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I made this &lt;a href=&quot;https://merchantandmills.com/store/books/the-workbook/&quot;&gt;Bantam vest&lt;/a&gt; about two years ago I think, just before I got pregnant. I can’t remember why I never got around to photographing it, probably because I had a baby bump.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This fabric is so nice. It’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://merchantandmills.com/store/cloth/tottorri-cross/&quot;&gt;Japanese seersucker printed with small crosses&lt;/a&gt;. When I first wore this top it was a little stiff but after a few washes it has softened up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love this vest pattern, but it’s too big for me now. Next time I’ll make a smaller size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/sewing/tottori-bantam.1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Vest from the front&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/sewing/tottori-bantam.2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Vest from the back&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/sewing/tottori-bantam.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Animated GIF&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/tottorri-cross-bantam</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/tottorri-cross-bantam</guid>
        
        
        <category>sewing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 36: t(&#39;_&#39;t)</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hello. Every time I get the week number or date wrong (a side effect of sloppy copy/pasting front matter around) &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alicebartlett/alicebartlett.github.io/commit/44069f44fc24495e78c1539677d9e5b3b66a1414#diff-3fac8e9ac51fdc825783e1c6f866d0b7&quot;&gt;Tom Stuart comments on the file on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, which then notifies me via my work email, which I then see on Monday. Anyway. I’ve fixed the problem now because I’ve written a bash script that will generate front matter for whatever the next Saturday is going to be. Thanks for your patience Tom. Please keep sending me corrections via GitHub t(‘_‘t).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Did everyone have a good bank holiday? Do people generally talk about how good May is? The weather is picking up, there are two bank holidays, your garden plants are looking good.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m off work next week because I haven’t had a holiday since Christmas. We’re going to stay around the house and do DIY while poor E goes to nursery and is none the wiser :^]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-36</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-36</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 35: Enjoyable foible</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I think it was Phil who shared &lt;a href=&quot;https://lrb.co.uk/v40/n18/tom-crewe/here-was-a-plague&quot;&gt;this LRB article about the Aids crisis&lt;/a&gt;. I might just think that because I know Phil reads LRB. Anyway - this article is very comprehensive and beautifully written. It is also absolutely devastating. I was born towards the end of the crisis so although I knew about it growing up I have slightly weird memories of it. There were some things I didn’t know and had never thought about, like the fact that to begin with nobody knew what it was, and there was no test for it. That at the beginning in the UK everyone thought it was “a US thing”. That there were special AIDS wards full of men just wasting away from the illness. That in 1987 only one funeral home would take Aids deaths. This bit:
&amp;gt; [June 1983, after the publishing a book called “How To Have Sex In An Epidemic”] Gonorrhoea diagnoses dropped by 73 per cent in San Francisco and more than halved in New York. It is likely that thousands of HIV infections were averted. But for more than half of all the gay men in both cities it was already too late.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I also learnt the origins of the phrase “patient zero”. It’s from a diagram mapping out HIV cases at the time thought to originate from a single air steward, Gaëtan Dugas. This was possible because Dugas kept names and addresses of the men if different cities that he had slept with. On the diagram he is marked with a letter “o” standing for “out of town”. Although people initially thought Dugas had spread HIV though being extremely promiscuous, it later emerged that the incubation period for HIV was much longer than people thought, meaning the men Dugas had slept with were likely already infected before they met Dugas.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I just watched the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netflix.com/title/81080637&quot;&gt;AOC documentary on Netflix&lt;/a&gt;. I cried several times during it. Can’t really explain why, it was just really moving.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve settled in to the new office. There are a number of things that I find entertaining about the build out - things that just haven’t been done quite right that I enjoy noticing but that don’t bother me. For example, the toilet locks are all at one of two orientations. For some, unlocked points down and locked points at 9pm, and for others, unlocked is at 9pm, and locked is up. I can see how this happens, there were lots of locks to fit and different people did them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The other enjoyable foible of the new building is that the handles are fitted on the wrong side of the revolving doors. The doors revolve in both directions but the way everyone wants to go is anti-clockwise. This would be fine but the handles are fitted for the clockwise direction. Remarkably, they have now put stickers on the doors to encourage people to push the doors anti-clockwise (IN CONTRADICTION TO THE HANDLES!). Sorry. Not interesting but it is true.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is national stationery week! We went on a little lunchtime trip to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.presentandcorrect.com/&quot;&gt;Present and Correct&lt;/a&gt;, which was very good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 10:28:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-35</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-35</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 34: Spritz your bum</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hello everyone. I am feeling a little unsettled this week. I think it’s because we moved office, but I’ve just not been able get into anything at work. Everything I did just felt like skating over the surface of a problem not properly understanding it and not properly dealing with it. Hopefully next week will be better.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Relatedly I am deep &lt;em&gt;deep&lt;/em&gt; into not knowing what is going on with our tech stack.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The new office is really nice. They have fizzy water on tap, and Japanese toilets that spritz your bum if you want. Now, when I feel like indulging I can go for a “luxury poo”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Feeling very much like the sort of person that responds to adverts that begin “Life got you down?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I read this &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyletter.com/waysofeating/letters/i-dream-of-canteens&quot;&gt;article about canteens&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/aanand&quot;&gt;@aanand&lt;/a&gt; shared via twitter. It’s great and really captures why I like the Sainsbury’s café so much. The Sainsbury’s café isn’t technically a canteen (and you’re not allowed to eat your own food there, although the staff don’t seem to mind if you do) but even on a Saturday lunchtime there is enough space to feel no pressure to move along, and there’s plenty of different types of seating, and lots of people enjoying a lunch out. I once saw a man throw up on the floor and nobody made a big deal out of it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I made another Kalle shirt. I’m going to make a third.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-34</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-34</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 33: Weird flex but ok</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I had a bit of a dicky tum tum this week. I never realised how often you get sick when you have a baby.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This was our last week in the current work building. Pretty excited to be moving to the new office. Obviously some of it will be rubbish but I view these kinds of things as boring resilience tests (I’m serious!). Also - nothing will compare to the suffering of the BERG move from the airy workshop space with skylights (now a WeWork) to the nylon carpet condemned Epworth House on City Road (now some other off-brand co-working space)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I think I might be having an existential cri- oh no sorry my period is due. Never mind.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have learnt a new put down: “Weird flex but ok”. You say it when someone is humblebragging about something. You know like this: “I’m the only person at work that uses Linux”, “Weird flex but ok”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have a new favourite Product Manager at work - Matt product manages the FT’s audio work but is also a PROFESSIONAL BAKER?!?!?! And every so often he brings in left-overs from his Saturday stall at Crystal Palace market. The cakes he brings in are absolutely delicious and totally beautiful. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.brettandbailey.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Brett &amp;amp; Bailey&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NEW BEYONCÉ!!! She is otherworldly. What a breathtaking performance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I had Thursday off this week with E. My god it was heaven. She was a dream. We went to Mayow Park twice, looked at plants, played shop with the other children in the park, went down the big slide.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On Good Friday we went to another park with some other friends, one of who is Edith’s “best friend” from nursery. E kept chasing her friend and trying to cuddle her and they appear to have their own language?!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-33</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-33</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
