<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The internet place for Alice Bartlett</title>
    <description>The website of Alice Bartlett. Front-end developer and internet person.</description>
    <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://alicebartlett.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 21:44:02 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 21:44:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weaknotes 18: Stop torturing me with your bad manicures</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Happy new year! We spent ours playing Pandemic Legacy 2.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I fell off the weaknotes wagon because I wrote a blog post about &lt;a href=&quot;http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/shared-parental-leave&quot;&gt;Shared Parental Leave&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/yearnotes-2018&quot;&gt;yearnotes&lt;/a&gt; instead. But this week I’m back baby!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I started work again on the 2nd. Hardly anybody was in so I got stuck into the emails and quick jobs that didn’t manage last year.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This month I’m going to run a workshop with my team about how to write concisely and clearly. I’ve had fun designing it - it’s given me an opportunity to dig out some favourite blog posts and style guides on writing. Just so we’re clear: there will be no mention of how to use apostrophes properly or do spelling.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We played “What became of Edith Finch” through Steam. It was good! Dark and spooky while also not too taxing. But! There is no way the lead character (Edith) has that manicure! What the hell! The Venn intersection of “Perfect french tips with square shaping” and “wears grey knitted fingerless mittens” is empty. I am happy to be a nail consultant on your next game or kickstarter product video, please just stop torturing me with your bad manicures.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/edith_finch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Edith Finch hands&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We watched Bandersnatch. I was quite bored by it tbh.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We watched LOOOOOFAAAAHHHHH. It was too scary for me. And also literally too dark? There were a few scenes that were too gloomy for me to be able to see what was going on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 10:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-18</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-18</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Yearnotes 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello! Yearnotes time again. To anyone unfamiliar, I write these at the end of every year for my own benefit mostly. They’re obviously very personal. I like reading about how other people’s years have gone, so if you’ve written some let me know!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a couple of big things that happened this year. I had a baby! We did some serious building work on our house! I changed roles at the Financial Times!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lets-get-the-baby-thing-out-of-the-way-first&quot;&gt;Let’s get the baby thing out of the way first&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edith was born in January at 3:57am weighing 8lb 11oz. She arrived after a six day long inpatient induction. In an almost dream like twist of events one of my best friends from sixth form college (with whom I had lost touch) turned up as my anaesthetist. After she was born we spent another five nights in hospital because of a suspected infection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I treasure the memories I have of her birth. I replay them and as they get further away I feel them morphing and becoming fuzzier. Luckily because the induction was so long I had some time to write some really long emails to the few people who knew I’d gone in for it. One day I’ll re-read those and remember it all again fresh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the get-go, Edith was perfect. Full of life, furious, soft. So soft. She’s now nearly one and loves climbing, hiding behind things, being chased and eating blueberries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her arrival has turned Lachie and I into very emotional people. We have the internal consistency of cottage cheese. From the moment she was born we both just turned to mush.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a year of new experiences. At each stage (the birth, being off work, going back to work) I was bracing for it to be awful and it just… wasn’t? The birth was objectively quite bad but at each stage there were lots of nice and proficient people around, and of course Lachie, so I quite enjoyed it. Then being off work with Edith turned out to be a piece of cake and very much aligned with things I already enjoy (loafing around, cuddles). Then going back to work was extremely empowering (more on this later).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lachie and I did shared parental leave, which I’ve written a &lt;a href=&quot;http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/shared-parental-leave&quot;&gt;whole other blog post about&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;house-house-house&quot;&gt;House! House! House!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the summer we spent eight weeks living at my parents house while we had some building work done on ours. We now have a much bigger kitchen and a loft conversion. Getting that done was quite tough going (especially on Lachie who still had to go to work in London). Our house is mostly back together now, and having a kitchen that fits more than two people in is really excellent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;great-content&quot;&gt;Great content&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started writing weaknotes. These are really for me to help me remember things. There is a small group of friends that I hope are interested in me personally enough to find anecdotes like “Edith did a poo as long as her whole arm” interesting. Though, on reflection, I doubt even my most loyal of friends is interested in that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also started doing Instagram videos while pushing Edith around in the pushchair. These came about because I was a bit bored on maternity leave and missed my grown-up friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk about Tampon Club for International Women’s Day when Edith was about 2 months old. Tampon Club has slowed, largely because I’ve been busy with a baby. But I really should get back to it. Write some blog posts. Send out some stickers. Bulk buy some tampons on Ali Ba Ba.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;making-things&quot;&gt;Making things&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year I didn’t get much sewing done as for most of the year I didn’t have a room to sew in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did have a very rewarding foray into screen printing and made some nice, if a little wonky, tea towels. I did this largely while Edith was napping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did quite a bit of embroidery, probably because it takes up much less space than machine sewing and is far more portable. I made a mobile for Edith’s room (a lot of which was done in hospital), a picture of a toucan (a lot of which was done while we were away over the summer) and some hanging toys for Edith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the year I bashed out two Jack Tar bags for Lachie’s brothers for Christmas. This is such a delightful pattern I’ll probably make it many more times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipNUdo7hMjZj83UHML7J51-nnhMMPSFEVVlAloUXDzHzIXvEhbOeOrHa0SAShGrCcw?key=Y2I0NjIzTlNvRllXVGtVWGthajFpOWJyczVab0FR&quot;&gt;There is a google photos album of things I made here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-job&quot;&gt;New job&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In October I went back to work after about 10 months away for having and looking after Edith. When I went back to work I took on a new role as Principal Engineer in the Customer Products team (that’s the team that looks after FT.com and the apps). I had been leading the Origami team for a while and I was worried I’d be bored when I went back so I wanted a new challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new role has been very enjoyable so far. Having a baby has changed my approach to work as it has left me much more focussed. Because I have to leave on time I don’t faff around as much as I used to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a new manager, Anna Shipman. Being managed by Anna is pretty amazing to be honest. She strives to be the best she can be at all times and it forces me to try my hardest too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pics&quot;&gt;Pics!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual I’ve made a photo album of the best things from 2018, but it doesn’t include any photos of Edith (except one of the back of her head) because we’re keeping her off the big old internet for now. Obviously she was a huge part of my year and also extremely cute, but unless we’re friends on Instagram you’ll just have to take my word for it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://photos.app.goo.gl/Smv8fmmzr6XjwBBQ9&quot;&gt;The album is here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 21:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/yearnotes-2018</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/yearnotes-2018</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
        <category>yearnotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Shared parental leave</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This year we had a daughter and my husband and I decided to make use of Shared Parental Leave (SPL). This legislation, brought in in 2014, allows two people (in our case the mother and father, but it could be two fathers, adoptive parents, whatever) to share one year’s leave between them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In February the Department for Business said that the uptake of SPL could be as low as 2% of the 285,000 couples that are eligible for it each year. I think SPL is amazing so I thought I’d write down what we did and why it was good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog post I’m going to talk about what my husband and I did.  I’m an a heterosexual relationship but the policy I’m talking about is available to same sex (or queer!) couples and couples adopting. In these cases there is a “Primary” and a “Secondary” parent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;before-spl-things-were-bad&quot;&gt;Before SPL, things were bad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before Shared Parental Leave, I would have been entitled to a full year off work (paid at whatever my employer’s leave policy is plus statutory). My husband would have been entitled to 2 weeks off work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This situation is a bit shit for everyone. Dads (or secondaries!) get less time with their babies. Mums (or primaries!) get less support from their partners. Women have to take a disproportionate career hit. Even in families where the dads want to pitch in equally, they’re not able to because they have to be back at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;with-shared-parental-leave-you-share-your-parental-leave&quot;&gt;With Shared Parental Leave you share your parental leave&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I AM NOT A HUMAN RESOURCES PROFESSIONAL&lt;/strong&gt; so here is the explanation from &lt;a href=&quot;https://sharedparentalleave.campaign.gov.uk/&quot;&gt;https://sharedparentalleave.campaign.gov.uk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Parents can share up to 50 weeks of leave and up to 37 weeks of pay and choose to take the leave and pay in a more flexible way (each parent can take up to 3 blocks of leave, more if their employer allows, interspersed with periods of work).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Eligible parents can be off work together for up to 6 months or alternatively stagger their leave and pay so that one of them is always at home with their baby in the first year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I found confusing to begin with was understanding the pay for shared parental leave. This is because initially I thought pay was moveable (eg I get 19 weeks full pay which I can take at any time). But actually all parental pay works by providing a rate for a specific week calculated from the when the first leave is taken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if I’m off during week 13, I’ll get the week 13 rate (which in my case because of the FT’s enhanced maternity policy, is full pay). If I’m off during week 20 I’ll get statutory pay (£145.18). It doesn’t matter if week 20 is my first week off, the pay for week 20 is the statutory allowance as my employer’s enhanced pay policy ends on week 19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My parental pay is calculated based on my employer’s policy, and my partner’s parental pay rate is calculated based on his employers policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-we-took-four-weeks-off-together&quot;&gt;First we took four weeks off together&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, enough with the poorly described legislation. What did my partner and I actually &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My partner’s employer (Microsoft) gives six week’s paid paternity leave in the UK, and he could take it in up two chunks. The Financial Times’s policy is the same for everybody (mothers, fathers, primaries, secondaries, etc). We all get 19 weeks leave fully paid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we took four weeks off together. I have no idea what we did during this time - it’s a total blur. I dimly recall lots of sleeping in? And some stumbling around? And cuddles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then my husband went back to work, and for seven and a half months I was the primary parent. I also took sole responsibility for all the cooking which allowed my partner to focus on work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;being-the-primary-parent-is-hard&quot;&gt;Being the primary parent is hard!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people don’t like the phrase “primary” parent. “It minimises the other parent’s role!”. Yes it does. But look. Having been both the primary and the secondary - the primary is different and a lot harder! At all times I had to be considering the needs of quite a needy small person. She can’t tell me if she’s hungry or tired or needs a nappy change. I have to remember if she’s poorly, if she’s currently refusing broccoli, what her favourite toys are, when she last pooed. Every day has to be, at a minimum, planned so that she’ll get some baby safe food and some time for naps. Sometimes it takes her an hour to eat a whole meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The secondary parent is still important. In the evenings being able to hand over responsibility, even just for the half hour before bed, was lovely. After a day of singing and chasing and tickling and playing and cleaning and feeding, I could have some quiet time to cook dinner. I didn’t especially like cooking until it came at the end of a day’s free play with a baby. Being able to follow a set of instructions uninterrupted and at the end have some delicious food became a real treat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;switching-roles&quot;&gt;Switching roles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite being a fairly equitable pair, while I was on leave, I was the the person who was leading decisions about our daughter. Even when my partner was there too, I was in charge. This was because I knew what she needed because I was pretty much always with her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we switched I realised how much I had become accustomed to looking after a baby. How rolling with the unpredictability of a child had become how I went about the day. Seeing my partner get to grips with this challenge made me realise what a shift it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going back to work at nine months was pretty easy, especially as I knew our daughter was with her dad. We chose a nine/three split because I wanted my partner to have a good chunk of time to get into being the primary. It took him a while to settle into the role so I’m glad we picked three months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose to express milk at work for three months when I went back. This was an awful experience to be honest. I’m somewhat on the fence about if I would recommend doing that to anyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tips-for-anyone-wanting-to-take-spl&quot;&gt;Tips for anyone wanting to take SPL&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engage your HR rep. My contact in the FT’s HR team described SPL as the most complicated piece of legislation they have to deal with. There are a huge number of ways to take SPL so talking through them with an expert is a really good idea.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try and have it so you both have some solo time. I gained so much empathy for what it was like being the secondary parent when I had to do it, and I know my husband learnt heaps from being the primary. Our daughter also got a lot from having a different parent running the show.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get yourself a spreadsheet. Organising maternity leave, paternity leave, shared parental leave, the annual leave you will still accrue while being on leave, all across multiple financial years is a logistical nightmare. I’m not going to share my spreadsheet because I think it probably only makes sense to me, but it was essential in working out what I was going to be paid, when I should return to work, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK - that’s it. I hope more people will take Shared Parental Leave. I must state again that &lt;strong&gt;I AM NOT A HUMAN RESOURCES PROFESSIONAL&lt;/strong&gt;, but if you have any questions about what we did that I haven’t covered here, just pop me an &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#105;&amp;#099;&amp;#101;&amp;#046;&amp;#098;&amp;#097;&amp;#114;&amp;#116;&amp;#108;&amp;#101;&amp;#116;&amp;#116;&amp;#064;&amp;#103;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 10:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/shared-parental-leave</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/shared-parental-leave</guid>
        
        
        <category>shared-parental-leave</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weaknotes 17: Minimum Viable Parenting</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lachie and I have caught some kind of stomach bug so spent the last few days either in bed or doing Minimum Viable Parenting on our daughter as we try not to barf. Rice cakes and grapes for dinner again darling! As luck would have it we are currently surrounded by family members who are all pitching in too.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My &lt;a href=&quot;http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/five-facts-about-smell&quot;&gt;post about smell&lt;/a&gt; has been put on Hacker News, which explains why about seven new people started following me on Twitter and why I got two emails about that post despite it being from 2014. Hello if you’re reading this from Hacker News. Though I’m too much of a chicken to go and read what people are saying about the post (what if someone is being mean to me on the internet!?!), I’ve seen some very flattering comments so thank you if you’re being nice about me.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I really want to know who is flying drones over Gatwick. At first I thought it was going to turn out to be some green activists like Extinction Rebellion but they have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2018/dec/20/tens-of-thousands-of-passengers-stranded-by-gatwick-airport-drones&quot;&gt;denied involvement&lt;/a&gt;. Now maybe it turns out there were no drones at all, which is entirely plausible to me, having listened to that Malcolm Gladwell podcast about  &lt;a href=&quot;http://revisionisthistory.com/episodes/28-the-imaginary-crimes-of-margit-hamosh&quot;&gt;collective hysterias&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[More about podcasts] I finished listening to the second series of &lt;a href=&quot;https://slate.com/slow-burn&quot;&gt;Slow Burn&lt;/a&gt;. This series is about the Clinton impeachment. This was much more gripping than the Nixon one somehow. I think maybe it was easier to follow. I keep trying to sum up what I think about Clinton having listened to this podcast but having tried a few takes none of them are very good so I’m just going to leave it at Clinton: a horrible man.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[Podcasts] On a car journey Lachie and I listened to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/episode/the-accidental-room/&quot;&gt;99% invisible episode about… a room in a mall?&lt;/a&gt;. The best I can summarise it is some people find a secret void in a mall which you have to get to by going through a series of weird gaps in between designed spaces. They manage to fill it with furniture and then they live in it. Not full time, but they spend days in it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 11:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-17</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-17</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weaknotes 16: A real crook!!</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[THE PUMPING CHRONICLES] I’m finished with the year! My last day of work was Monday and when I go back in three weeks I don’t intend to pump.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2018/11/27/style/what-is-inside-this-internet-rabbit-hole.html&quot;&gt;something good from Jenny Odell&lt;/a&gt; about getting sucked down a rabbit hole of shady semi-fraudulent Amazon stores. I felt like I needed a &lt;a href=&quot;https://crazywalls.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;crazy wall&lt;/a&gt; to keep track of all of this by the end. (Via&lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyletter.com/feministfriday&quot;&gt;Feminist Friday&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I finished listening to “Slow Burn” season one, which is a podcast about The Watergate scandal. I had it on while sewing. It was OK - not gripping enough that I felt the need to pause it while I used my machine which is ideal. The main reason I listened to it was because I don’t know much about President Nixon. Look you guys - here is what I learnt: Nixon was a real crook!!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[THINGS MY DAUGHTER WILL BRING UP IN THERAPY IN A FEW YEARS TIME] E did a poo &lt;em&gt;literally&lt;/em&gt; as long as her arm in the bath last night. It was enormous. I yelled “CODE BROWN!!!” and Lachie rushed up from downstairs. When Lachie saw it he gasped and said “BLOODY HELL! BLOODDDDDDY HELLLLLL!”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’re trying to get some stuff finished with our house at the moment. Polyfilling in some bits. Repainting some bits. You know. Odds and ends. Next year Lachie and I will both be back at work full time so this Christmas period feels like a last hurrah before we properly have no free time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve started sewing with Dry Oilskin and oh my god it is amazing to sew with. So easy to mark! So easy to cut! No ironing! &lt;a href=&quot;https://merchantandmills.com/product-category/cloth/utility/&quot;&gt;Merchant and Mills&lt;/a&gt; have a lovely selection. I was a bit squeamish about the name “Oxblood Red” but the actual colour is gorgeous. (Side note: Merchant and Mills’s website is so slow, my god)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I need to move all my sewing off of Tumblr.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;WHAT THE HACK IS HAPPENING IN POLITICS. I don’t write about Brexit because it feels utterly pointless. I assume everyone reading this agrees with me that the referendum was a gun with which we (the British public) immediately shot ourselves in the foot and nearly everything since has been an utter shambles. I could go on and on about it but what would be the point - you all agree with me! Anyway. I must mark this week’s developments as being even more absurd than usual somehow. So this paragraph is that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 22:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-16</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-16</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weaknotes 15: Properly hydrated</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some things I learnt at work this week:
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;In a study about hydration, people who were properly hydrated performed 14% better at cognitive tasks than people who were not properly hydrated.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;In a mass productivity study the most productive people were those who averaged 52 minutes uninterrupted work and 17 minutes break.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It’s a good idea to count to seven in your head after you have said “is everyone happy to move on?” if chairing a meeting in order to give anyone with introverted preferences time to think and then speak.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“James’” is the US English way to do singular possessive proper nouns. “James’s” is British.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One of the things I did at work this week was cry in some training. I don’t normally feel particularly embarrassed about crying but this was mortifying. It was in front of three strangers and a man named Rob. Having never seen three of the people in that room before in my life, of course, now I see them everywhere.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I can’t watch that new David Attenborough thing. I get too sad.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I spent the whole day sewing and now my fingers hurt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 22:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-15</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-15</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weaknotes 14: Eels writhing across a canteen floor</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;These weaknotes are late but they’re good! Poetry! German Shepherds! Eels!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aftertheflood.com/&quot;&gt;Max Gadney&lt;/a&gt; reminded me of the phrase “typing for coins” which is how Jones used to describe bits of consultancy at BERG. &lt;em&gt;Tippy-tappy! Typing for coins!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.entertainmentvine.com/online/2017/03/interview-with-game-designer-marsha-jean-falco/&quot;&gt;Did you know the game Set was developed originally to determine if epilepsy in German Shepherds&lt;/a&gt;. Yet another fascinating thing I’ve learnt from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyletter.com/feministfriday&quot;&gt;Feminist Friday newsletter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Last week was a bit of a stretch tbh. Forces outside of my control led to two away days in one week, which then pushed all my other work into the remaining two days. I’m also still spending about 1.5 hours a day expressing milk.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am not a productivity nut. I find those people… Embarrassing. But! &lt;a href=&quot;https://betterhumans.coach.me/how-to-set-up-your-iphone-for-productivity-focus-and-your-own-longevity-bb27a68cc3d8?gi=88d8bb186ec0&quot;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; does have some good tips about making your iPhone not quite so horribly distracting. I implemented quite a few of the suggestions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are some absolute bangers on &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/user/russelldavies/playlist/6yeWyDCRLuxaAcZaXDVZI5?si=3Nn27bltTViOW0lyF_6U4Q&quot;&gt;Russell’s Poker Playlist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Short sentences / Strong verbs” was the title of a Revisionist History episode that I listened to this week. I googled the phrase because it sounded clever and I want to learn how to write good.  Maybe I’ll try to deploy some strong verbs. I think I’m OK at the short sentences.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People who just say “hi Alice” on slack and then don’t type anything? Please type something. I know you think you’re being polite but actually from “hi” I can’t tell what you want or how long it will take me to answer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Someone suggested we should be building ‘frictionless’ experiences the other day. I asked them to elaborate and they had a great point about sign up flows that I didn’t disagree with. But I loathe the word ‘frictionless’ in this context. Friction is what is keeping me on my chair right now. It stops us all from sliding all over the place like eels writhing across a canteen floor. Friction in services helps us make decisions. Amazon’s sign-up to Amazon Prime at the checkout is so frictionless I keep frigging doing it by accident and not realising. Friction is useful and important.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This has reminded me of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.elasticspace.com/2013/03/no-to-no-ui/comment-page-1&quot;&gt;No to noUI from 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And don’t get me started on ‘delight’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/samccone/&quot;&gt;Sam Saccone’s Instagram&lt;/a&gt; is in my top five for his commitment to a theme.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developers and designers that work at the FT and read it with an ad blocker are a puzzle to me. How are you going to appreciate the user experience of most of our readers if you block ads?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I went to the post office today to post a surprise present for someone. I’m &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; chuffed to have found such a great gift for this person - weird, difficult to come by, inexpensive - that it was entirely worth going to the post office to send it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I was in Wiltshire this weekend, we did some good walks, I will treasure the memory of my friend talking to a pony while we lifted the running pram over a stile into its field. There were 10 stiles across the whole walk and I have ruined my trainers from the mud but I have no regrets.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instyle.com/celebrity/britney-spears-perfume-billion-dollar-business&quot;&gt;This article about how good Britney Spears is at perfume&lt;/a&gt; was really good.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We drove past Slough on the way back from Wiltshire. I hadn’t read &lt;a href=&quot;http://www-cdr.stanford.edu/intuition/Slough.html&quot;&gt;Slough&lt;/a&gt; by John Betjeman in a while. I looked it up and it does have some cracking bits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Come friendly bombs and fall on Slough!&lt;br /&gt;
It isn’t fit for humans now,&lt;br /&gt;
There isn’t grass to graze a cow.&lt;br /&gt;
Swarm over, Death!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Come, bombs and blow to smithereens&lt;br /&gt;
Those air -conditioned, bright canteens,&lt;br /&gt;
Tinned fruit, tinned meat, tinned milk, tinned beans,&lt;br /&gt;
Tinned minds, tinned breath.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mess up the mess they call a town-&lt;br /&gt;
A house for ninety-seven down&lt;br /&gt;
And once a week a half a crown&lt;br /&gt;
For twenty years.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And get that man with double chin&lt;br /&gt;
Who’ll always cheat and always win,&lt;br /&gt;
Who washes his repulsive skin&lt;br /&gt;
In women’s tears:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And smash his desk of polished oak&lt;br /&gt;
And smash his hands so used to stroke&lt;br /&gt;
And stop his boring dirty joke&lt;br /&gt;
And make him yell.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;But spare the bald young clerks who add&lt;br /&gt;
The profits of the stinking cad;&lt;br /&gt;
It’s not their fault that they are mad,&lt;br /&gt;
They’ve tasted Hell.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It’s not their fault they do not know&lt;br /&gt;
The birdsong from the radio,&lt;br /&gt;
It’s not their fault they often go&lt;br /&gt;
To Maidenhead&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And talk of sport and makes of cars&lt;br /&gt;
In various bogus-Tudor bars&lt;br /&gt;
And daren’t look up and see the stars&lt;br /&gt;
But belch instead.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In labour-saving homes, with care&lt;br /&gt;
Their wives frizz out peroxide hair&lt;br /&gt;
And dry it in synthetic air&lt;br /&gt;
And paint their nails.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Come, friendly bombs and fall on Slough&lt;br /&gt;
To get it ready for the plough.&lt;br /&gt;
The cabbages are coming now;&lt;br /&gt;
The earth exhales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 09:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-14</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-14</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weaknotes 13: Thank you internet stranger!</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I feel like a ghost.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am very behind (like, six months) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://tampon.club&quot;&gt;Tampon Club&lt;/a&gt; emails. Sorry if you’re waiting for stickers. I have lost them in my house somewhere. I know. I know.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have realised a thing about the diet coke ad that I talked about &lt;a href=&quot;http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-12&quot;&gt;last week&lt;/a&gt;. The man in this ad is actually walking past (and greets) the woman from the April version of the ad! My small mind was quite pleased to have noticed that.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I got a nice email from someone that I don’t know to say they like my weaknotes. Thank you internet stranger! I don’t know why people read these, but it’s nice when people do.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At work something cool happened, which I’ll have to be deliberately vague about, but basically the FT data team has been working on some machine learning stuff and unlike a lot of machine learning things it actually seems quite good and well thought out and like it might serve a useful purpose? Anyway, perhaps someone will write something proper about it somewhere one day. I hope they do.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Another work update. The Editor of the FT is an extremely impressive person. Even my attempts to describe how impressive he is feel clumsy and stupid so I won’t bother. Anyway. Here is the thing. I once stood behind him in the queue at the canteen where this incredibly articulate and well-read man lamented the fact that they had stopped selling ham and cheese croissants. &lt;em&gt;Ham and cheese&lt;/em&gt;. “He puts his trousers on one leg at a time just like everybody else”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anna has written a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.annashipman.co.uk/jfdi/interviewing-fairly.html&quot;&gt;good post on hiring&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;OK I’m going to try and work out where those Tampon Club stickers are now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Once Lachie heard this and decided to prove that it was possible to put a pair of pants on two legs at a time. It took several attempts but he did manage to jump into them eventually. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 09:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-13</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-13</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weaknotes 12: Phoney and insincere</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is a diet coke ad I get a lot when watching Community on All4. Everyone on the internet &lt;a href=&quot;http://adturds.co.uk/2018/11/13/diet-coke-mango-advert-superbad-superannoying-superstupid/&quot;&gt;absolutely hates this advert&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.campaignlive.co.uk/article/turkey-week-diet-cokes-joyless-because-i-can-ad-doesnt-feel-good/1460587&quot;&gt;and the others in the series&lt;/a&gt;) but I completely love it. Obviously Diet Coke tastes disgusting, but this guy doesn’t care! He likes it! “You’ve just got to like what you like” he tells me. Thank you Diet Coke man, I will!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Edith can say “herro” now, though more often she just waves. She will also (sometimes) put her hands above her head if you say “reach for the skyyyy” which is absurdly cute.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The canteen only had smooth peanut butter or “peanut free” peanut butter on Tuesday morning. Not sure why you’d want to eat peanut free peanut butter. Maybe if you had a peanut allergy but then it’s right next to the peanut butter in the canteen and someone might have stuck a peanutty knife into it, so would you risk it?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I still really like being back at work. When dudes used to tell me “my wife doesn’t work but oh boy is looking after a child a full time job!!!” I found it kind of phoney and insincere but having properly done both I can tell you that, for me, looking after a child is significantly harder than going to work every day. That probably has to do with my job in part. I’m really pleased we’re doing shared parental leave so Lachie can do full time baby wrangling.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Edith has another cold, and can only sleep if I’m holding her otherwise she coughs and wakes herself up. I did kind of have plans for this naptime such as publishing my weaknotes but instead I’m in a gloomy room slowly losing feeling in my arm.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I tweeted about this once I think, but it came up again this week. I’ve invented a measure for how similar two people look. The “Bartlett Number” of two individuals is the lowest age of a child that can draw a picture of the two individuals such that it’s obvious which person in the picture is which.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m sewing another &lt;a href=&quot;https://grainlinestudio.com/shop/women/tamarack-jacket-pdf/&quot;&gt;Tamarack&lt;/a&gt;. It will be my third &lt;a href=&quot;http://sewing.butt.kitchen/post/133426538028/grainline-tamarack-jacket&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=&quot;http://sewing.butt.kitchen/post/154044565363/tamarack-2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 21:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-12</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-12</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weaknotes 11: What is the deal</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lachie has taken Edith out so I am back in bed eating an out of date chocolate muffin which I have microwaved so it will taste less stale.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Working is good isn’t it? It’s quite busy and feels like there is a lot to do, but I think I am effectively prioritising things. I’m trying very hard not to do any work at the weekends or evenings but I desperately want to because it’s extremely satisfying.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Edith has some suspicious spots that seem a little… chicken poxy? I have spent too much time looking at disgusting rashes on the internet since having a baby tbh.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oh god this muffin is good&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the topic of muffins, isn’t it awful when you eat a muffin only to realise it’s jam filled? Yes it is awful.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is the deal with people who use South Park characters for their slack icons? &lt;em&gt;What is their deal?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Having to pump at work while also having a periods reminds me of this tweet - possibly the greatest tweet of all time: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/IamEnidColeslaw/status/351425828606849024&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/IamEnidColeslaw/status/351425828606849024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 21:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-11</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-11</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
