<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The internet place for Alice Bartlett</title>
    <description>The website of Alice Bartlett. Front-end developer and internet person.</description>
    <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://alicebartlett.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 11:23:18 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 11:23:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 26: Not to brag</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are you still cutting off two sides of your PDF clothes patterns and then sticking them together like a loser? &lt;a href=&quot;https://itch-to-stitch.com/assemble-pdf-patterns-quick-way/&quot;&gt;TRY THIS COMPLETELY PARADIGM SHIFTING METHOD FOR ASSEMBLING PATTERNS&lt;/a&gt;. Thank you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tessthornton&quot;&gt;Tessa&lt;/a&gt; for showing me the true way.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/edds&quot;&gt;Edds&lt;/a&gt; has joined the team I’m in at the FT. I feel absolutely giddy at the prospect of working with him again.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Speaking of which did you know that a Gallup poll found that women with a work best friend are twice as likely to be engaged with their work than those that don’t. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gallup.com/workplace/237530/item-best-friend-work.asp&quot;&gt;Poll&lt;/a&gt;. Not to brag, but I have &lt;em&gt;several&lt;/em&gt; work best friends which would explain why I am so incredibly engaged with my job.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[Pro tip] After a rubbish day, sack everything you possibly can off, except brushing your teeth really well. Do the back ones, get the bit behind your lower front where the dentist always goes HAM to scrape the plaque off. Brush your tongue. Do your best. There. Now at least you’ve ended the day on a high. Pat yourself on the back and go to bed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There was more for these weeknotes. Possibly something about how E is mortally afraid of her Grandad and will try to hide whenever he comes on the video call? Maybe something about how hard it is to dress for work when you want both software engineers AND business folk to take you seriously &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; when you’re a woman. I don’t know I’ve forgotten.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 09:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-26</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-26</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 25: Smash that interactive rebase</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Did a workshop on Git this week with [Tatiana][https://twitter.com/binaryberry]. It was super good. When it came to the exercises, it was the most interested I’ve ever seen people in a workshop. People really wanted to smash that interactive rebase!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Could I do a 40 minute talk on Git? Is that interesting? I need to do a 40 minute talk on &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;. I have a long time to figure out what though so maybe it’s should be something else.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I assembled a cold frame for my plant babies. After the builders trashed my plants last year I’m really excited for this year’s growing season. Going to feed my houseplants properly and grow sweat peas, phlox, and thunbergia.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I did some gardening last weekend. Sawed my thumb a bit but the garden is looking much tidier.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My sewing class has finished. I’ve nearly completed the trousers, I just need to do some hand sewing. I will write about them here once I’ve photographed them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve just finished &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/stitcher/the-dream&quot;&gt;this podcast&lt;/a&gt; on multi-level marketing. If you enjoy reading about pyramid schemes then it’s probably worth it. It focusses on how MLMs have become so common in the US, and so legally difficult to pursue. It could be about 50% shorter - as with all podcasts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lachie has eaten TWO almond magnum icecreams by midday on Saturday. He bought one for himself and one for me one in case I wanted one, but since I’d literally just finished a fry up, I wasn’t really in the mood. Lachie had also just eaten a fried breakfast but he is an animal so that explains that. He said I’d left him with “literally no choice but to eat a second magnum”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We watched Russian Doll. I didn’t like the first few episodes much but it really got going around episode three and then we hammered through it in under a week. And the ending! Ugh the ending was so good! I almost hope there isn’t another series because they tied this one up so neatly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The weather is on the up which is making me feel good until I realise it’s probably unusually warm because of climate change and then I remember that the insects are dying and the ice is melting. Hurrrrgh I feel sick.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Byeeeeeeeee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 20:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-25</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-25</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 24: I&#39;m Pauly, from New Joysey</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Normally when I see someone is doing weeknotes about their actual jobs I think “oh here we go, this’ll be extremely boring” so imagine my surprise when I clicked on &lt;a href=&quot;https://demotive.com/weeknotes/2019/02/08/&quot;&gt;Mat’s second instalment&lt;/a&gt; which begins with the sentence:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Another week of shining visions of joined-up healthcare being ground to dust by grim reality as we continue to investigate service propositions for hooking 111 online into pharmacies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It ends with something even better but I don’t want to spoil it for you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The other day a friend told me she absolutely hates getting compliments because she finds them incredibly patronising. This has left me with a paranoia that every time I say “well done” the person I’ve said it to is thinking “thanks - fuck you!”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Because of the way the character “Pauly” in the Sopranos pronounces his name (with a New Jersey accent it’s more like “poorly”) now in our house when you’re ill you say “I’m Pauly, from New Joysey”. It’s just a thing we do, OK? Anyway at the beginning of this week I was extremely Pauly from New Jersey.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Last week I did some pairing with my colleague &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/_magspie&quot;&gt;Maggie&lt;/a&gt;. It was not very interesting work, but it was great to get to pair with someone, especially someone cool and fun like Maggie. I think we both learnt some stuff and the task I was dealing with got done much quicker because Maggie was co-pilot. I don’t get to write a lot of code anymore so this kind of thing is basically living the dream.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Well done to the leet hax0r that has taken up my old tumblr and started posting spam to it. I had forgotten to delete the DNS record after I deleted the Tumblr so now at my domain there is a load of crap about using photoshop. I have deleted it now, don’t worry. In retrospect, I should have hung on to the Tumblr name, but I held it close to me, asked myself “does alicesews.tumblr.com spark joy?” and then acted accordingly. Marie Kondo hasn’t, to my knowledge, done an episode on tidying up old tumblrs but I hope she’ll point out that the second you “delete” a tumblr you free it up to be used by anyone else, and &lt;em&gt;obviously&lt;/em&gt; delete the corresponding DNS record you n00b.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am tiiiired. Help me.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If I was going to get into catfishing I would use &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rowanmanning&quot;&gt;Rowan Manning’s&lt;/a&gt; profile pic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This week 5 of us had our third away-day to sort out the career paths and progression at work. After 3 days we have a rough bunch of agreed competencies and a plan for shipping them as a versioned alpha, which feels amazing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’re moving office in May and our new bogs have those Japanese computerised bum hole washing toilets that also sing to you. I would complain about this but we also got some gender neutral bathrooms so I think everyone got what they wanted.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Just did week 2 of my sewing class. I kind of zoned out last week when Julie told us what the homework was and so I ended up doing probably 2 hours more than everyone else, which is significant when a class is 3 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-24</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-24</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 23: Edited a hunk</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2019/02/11/a-suspense-novelists-trail-of-deceptions&quot;&gt;this about pathological liar and author Dan Mallory&lt;/a&gt; after Dan W tweeted it. I didn’t really want to be reading it, but it sucked me in. I went to school with a pathological liar but she’s probably grown out of it by now. She used to make up all kinds of odd things - her dad (a GP) was being hounded by the press because of some scandal; she wrote a piece of music herself that I recognised to be the Moonlight Sonata 🤷‍♀️; one day she came to school and pretended for a whole day to have lost her voice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are new emoji. Very excited for the flamingo. Not so excited for the small dick emoji.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve started a sewing class at Sew Over It. I’m going to make some chroma-key cigarette pants. The new Sew Over It shop is lovely and spacious and bright. I’ve got the same brilliant teacher that I had last time (Julie). She’s basically a pattern savant - can look at any bum/thigh/crotch and say what changes to the pattern need to be made.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We started watching that Bill Clinton docu on Channel 4. It’s good! There is some very eighties hair happening.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This week edited a hunk for the first time using git. I felt very alive and very powerful to be honest.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[Chris Noth watch] OMG Chris Noth is in Catastrophe and he has white hair and a moustache!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-23</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-23</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 22: Antithesis of hunky</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We mutha-flippin made it to mutha-flipping February my dudes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This week I’ve been moving my sewing tumblr over to this site. I’ve done 30 posts since 2014. It’s been interesting to look back at 5 years worth of sewing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Edith has finally kicked her nursery cold. It’s like “freshers flu” but you’re a baby. Gosh she is adorable. On Tuesday I said to her “Edith can I have a cuddle?” and she literally stopped what she was doing (pretending to drink from a cup) and crawled over to me, rested her head on my knee and said “ahh-hahh”. rip me.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I went to see Hamilton on Thursday. I don’t know why I keep going to musicals. I don’t actually like them but every few years I forget and end up going to one. I actually walked out of Avenue Q at the interval. Hamilton was good? For a musical.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s gotten to that bit of winter where everything is a grind. I &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; the first peeps of spring will make me feel better and remind me how weak I am for being so affected by the weather. DO NOT tell me to get a SAD lamp.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m getting a lot of wear out of my TN31. It’s so long and cosy, I’m really happy with how it turned out.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I was using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git add --p&lt;/code&gt; this week and it made me wonder: “What is the hunkiest emoji”? I had a quick look and I think it might be “man playing water polo” 🤽‍ On the one hand, he’s shirtless (v hunky) on the other hand though he’s wearing a swimming cap (the antithesis of hunky).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hot or Not but for emoji?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 16:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-22</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-22</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TN31 Parka</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yahoo! Tumblr does really awful things to my photographs so I’m moving all my sewing posts over here now. Sorry if you dgaf about sewing or pictures of me wearing clothes. This post is from literally today. I’ll import the rest later. I don’t know what happens with RSS if you add really old posts. Something we can find out together. This will be the third time I’ve moved my sewing project write ups. Originally they lived on Flickr, then they went to Tumblr, now they’re here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made the &lt;a href=&quot;https://merchantandmills.com/store/patterns/the-tn31-parka/&quot;&gt;TN31 Parka from Merchant and Mills&lt;/a&gt; after seeing Nat’s mustard version and being extremely impressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cut a size 12. It has plenty of ease so still feels quite big.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fabric-and-notions&quot;&gt;Fabric and notions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The outer fabric is &lt;a href=&quot;https://merchantandmills.com/store/cloth/fern-dry-oilskin/&quot;&gt;dry oilskin in ‘Fern’&lt;/a&gt; from Merchant and Mills&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I lined it with some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.minervacrafts.com/shop/fabric/dress-fabrics/c3923-m-cotton-winceyette-flannel-dress-fabric?colour=Black&quot;&gt;black brushed cotton&lt;/a&gt; from Minerva Crafts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The neck ribbing is also from M&amp;amp;M, it’s the &lt;a href=&quot;https://merchantandmills.com/store/cloth/jansson-rib/&quot;&gt;Jansson Rib&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The buttons are &lt;a href=&quot;https://merchantandmills.com/store/trims/khaki-corozo-22mm/&quot;&gt;these ones&lt;/a&gt; from M&amp;amp;M too&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sewing-notes&quot;&gt;Sewing notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was quite a tricky sew. The lined version is basically two coats stuck together (that’s how lining works, duh). Because you can’t iron dry oilskin it’s not so easy to just iron out sloppy sewing (which is my usual trick). Dry oilskin is also very unforgiving to being unpicked as it leaves marks where the stitches were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards the end I began to struggle a lot with the volume of fabric I was trying to move about. It was quite heavy to there are a few wonky bits where I had a bit of a fight with the coat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The neck was also very difficult to sew. I’m not sure I exactly nailed it, but I really love the ribbing anyway so I can live with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What did I like about this pattern? Well, the finished item is lovely and warm. It has four pockets which is ideal for my four hands. The neckline (although I fudged it a bit) is really cute. The hidden buttons are also a really nice touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/tn31.1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;TN31&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/tn31.2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;TN31&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/tn31.3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;TN31&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/tn31.4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;TN31&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/tn31.5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;TN31&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/tn31.6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;TN31&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 09:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/tn31-parka</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/tn31-parka</guid>
        
        
        <category>sewing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 21: IS IT APT? IS IT FUNNY? IS IT NEW?</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lukekavanagh_&quot;&gt;Luke&lt;/a&gt; showed me where to find the Financial Times style guide. I have spent hours reading it. As you would expect there is lots to enjoy. The bits about journalistic cliché’s are my favourite. Things like:
&amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;scrambling&lt;/strong&gt;
There are too many people scrambling to do something in the FT. Let them hurry if they must or even try.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The bit about apostrophes is good too:
&amp;gt; The apostrophe (‘) is not dead but it is dying. It has left Earls Court and St Andrews, but not yet Regent’s Park; and it has vanished from companies such as Barclays Bank and Currys, and magazine titles such as Farmers Weekly. […]&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This advice about puns needs to be more widely embraced:
&amp;gt;&lt;strong&gt;puns&lt;/strong&gt;
[…]
&amp;gt; It is unreasonable to expect all […] puns to be banned from the pages of the FT, particularly in features, in Weekend FT and on the Arts page. But think carefully before you commit yourself: is the pun apt? is it funny? is it new?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IS IT APT? IS IT FUNNY? IS IT NEW? Next time someone puns near me (I know who it will be, I sit near a &lt;em&gt;prolific&lt;/em&gt; punner) I’m going to say this to them.
* &lt;a href=&quot;https://natbuckley.co.uk/2019/01/20/weeknotes-1-tv-ads-and-business-models/&quot;&gt;Nat is doing weeknotes&lt;/a&gt; and they are much more interesting than mine. I’m furious!
* What is the German compound noun for when you’re upset but basically keeping it together and then somebody is nice to you and you fall into a million pieces?
* Shout out to my fellow disciples of “12-1 is the one true lunch hour”
* wooof I am very tired this week.
* I listened to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.originsthepodcast.com/&quot;&gt;the rest of this Origins podcast about Sex and The City&lt;/a&gt;. It’s put together quite poorly but some of the interviews are so good. Worth it for how cross Chris Noth is alone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 09:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-21</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-21</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 20: Phoning in</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Weaknotes twenty!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Edith turned one year old this week. I’m considering getting a second opinion on that though, because there is no way she’s one. I can’t accept it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I started sewing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://merchantandmills.com/store/patterns/the-tn31-parka/&quot;&gt;Fern Green TN31 Parka from M&amp;amp;M&lt;/a&gt; this weekend. I realised recently that all the coats I’ve ever made have been navy blue, this is an exciting departure!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Edith started nursery this week, although she got a fever on Thursday so they sent her home. I had to look after her on Thursday and Friday which was pretty rough to be honest! Other than the sickness she has taken to nursery OK. Not too many tears.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m phoning in weaknotes this week because it’s Sunday night and I have some other things to do before I go to bed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I listened to the first episode of this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.originsthepodcast.com/&quot;&gt;Origins podcast about Sex and The City&lt;/a&gt;. It was good. I have complicated feelings about SATC. I’ve seen every episode multiple times but if you were to say to me “Alice, Sex and The City is rubbish” I’d say “you’re not wrong”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;That’s it Byeeeeeeeeee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 09:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-20</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-20</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 19: In practice RIP my quads</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I met with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kimber_long&quot;&gt;Kimberly&lt;/a&gt;, the blog editor at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloodygoodperiod.com/&quot;&gt;Bloody Good Period&lt;/a&gt; this week. She works at the FT. She was brilliant - Bloody Good are brilliant. We’re going to team up on something menstruation related though we haven’t figured out what yet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I did some circuits at lunchtime which &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.annashipman.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Anna&lt;/a&gt; runs. In theory a great idea - exercising with nice people in a park. In practice RIP my quads.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Today we are hosting 8 (EIGHT) one year olds and their parents.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Edith started nursery this week. The only criticism I have of the nursery staff is they aren’t impressed enough by how amazing our daughter is. Like… look at her perfectly symmetrical bald head? see how good she is at climbing on the table? see how funny she is when she tries to play hide and seek? Don’t her eyes seem especially big and cute to you? Anyway. I suppose they’re just trying to be professional.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I found the Tampon Club stickers finally.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I listened to some of Matt Irvine Brown’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://musicforshuffle.com/sketches/&quot;&gt;Music for Shuffle&lt;/a&gt; again on Thursday when I was trying to focus. Still so good!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 09:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-19</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-19</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>rip Flickr</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Flickr is going to start charging for accounts and deleting photos from free accounts over 1000. I stopped using Flickr a few years ago because it seemed really likely that it was going to go down the shitter in Yahoo!’s custody.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m pleased that’s not going to happen but since I’ve stopped using it, I’m not going to start again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a look back through all my favourites and all the photos I’m tagged in. Nearly all of the ones not taken by me are from 2011-2013 when I was at BERG. Here are some of my faves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;baby-me-at-interesting-2008&quot;&gt;Baby me at Interesting 2008&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am 21 in this photo! I recall Interesting 2008 being really exciting. I made a last-minute decision to go with &lt;a href=&quot;https://rooreynolds.com&quot;&gt;Roo&lt;/a&gt; as he had a spare ticket. I was supposed to be moving house that weekend but decided to leave it until until Sunday. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/annapickard&quot;&gt;Anna Pickard&lt;/a&gt; said the word “plinth” on stage while nearly crying with laughter and then, after, I met her and she told me she always wears special shoes on stage. An event I clearly thought was important enough to remember. And look! &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamesbridle.com/&quot;&gt;James Bridle&lt;/a&gt; is in the background. I didn’t actually meet him properly until June 2010. I know the date because there is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/russss/4712449350/in/album-72157624303682296/&quot;&gt;another photo on Flickr from the last.fm bbq that I met him at&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/interesting08.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Interesting&quot; /&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/bowbrick/2599391457/in/photosof-alicebartlett/&quot;&gt;Original&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lots-of-drinking-outside-pubs&quot;&gt;Lots of drinking outside pubs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think maybe 50% of these photos are taken by &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/timoarnall&quot;&gt;Timo&lt;/a&gt; and are of BERG and BERG-adjacent people drinking outside pubs.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/tom-alice-joe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Alice, Tom and James&quot; /&gt;
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/timo/6227330642/in/photosof-alicebartlett/&quot;&gt;Original&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pizza.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pizza!&quot; /&gt;
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/timo/8280980308/in/album-72157647033256218/&quot;&gt;Original&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;doing-crosswords-at-berg&quot;&gt;Doing crosswords at BERG&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://designswarm.com/&quot;&gt;Alex D-S&lt;/a&gt; left a Guardian cryptic crossword out at the Brig and from then on we used to do them at lunchtime. Timo really hates cryptic crosswords.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/alice-denise-crossword.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Alice and Denise Wilton&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/alice-phil-crossword.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Alice and Phil Gyford&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/crossword.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Crossword at lunch&quot; /&gt;
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/timo/6477288445/in/album-72157647033256218/&quot;&gt;Originals&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/timo/6459405277/in/album-72157647033256218/&quot;&gt;are&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/timo/6918670183/in/photosof-alicebartlett/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;alice-counting-screws-quite-loudly&quot;&gt;Alice counting screws (quite loudly)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember this really clearly. God that office was grim. I was doing inventory for screws for Little Printer right next to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gyford.com&quot;&gt;Phil&lt;/a&gt;. Poor Phil.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/counting-screws.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Counting screws&quot; /&gt;
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/philgyford/11325773703/in/photosof-alicebartlett/&quot;&gt;Original by Phil here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-newcastle-when-me-and-mark-hurrell-wore-matching-outfits&quot;&gt;In Newcastle when Me and Mark Hurrell wore matching outfits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally we’ve made it past 2013. This photo was taken by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.benterrett.com/&quot;&gt;Ben Terrett&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/benterrett/12769099183/in/photosof-alicebartlett/&quot;&gt;Original with Ben’s dad’s comments is here&lt;/a&gt;. This was taken when I was at GDS. We were on a trip to Newcastle to hire for an HMRC centre up there. We did two days of Civil Service interviews in hotel rooms with the beds removed. My main memories were feeling a bit sweaty. I sewed that top myself.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/alice-mark.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Alice and Mark Hurrell&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 22:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/rip-flickr</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/rip-flickr</guid>
        
        
        <category>photos</category>
        
        <category>flickr</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
