<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The internet place for Alice Bartlett</title>
    <description>The website of Alice Bartlett. Front-end developer and internet person.</description>
    <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://alicebartlett.co.uk/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 16:52:54 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 16:52:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weaknotes 22: antithesis of hunky</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We mutha-flippin made it to mutha-flipping February my dudes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This week I’ve been moving my sewing tumblr over to this site. I’ve done 30 posts since 2014. It’s been interesting to look back at 5 years worth of sewing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Edith has finally kicked her nursery cold. It’s like “freshers flu” but you’re a baby. Gosh she is adorable. On Tuesday I said to her “Edith can I have a cuddle?” and she literally stopped what she was doing (pretending to drink from a cup) and crawled over to me, rested her head on my knee and said “ahh-hahh”. rip me.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I went to see Hamilton on Thursday. I don’t know why I keep going to musicals. I don’t actually like them but every few years I forget and end up going to one. I actually walked out of Avenue Q at the interval. Hamilton was good? For a musical.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s gotten to that bit of winter where everything is a grind. I &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; the first peeps of spring will make me feel better and remind me how weak I am for being so affected by the weather. DO NOT tell me to get a SAD lamp.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m getting a lot of wear out of my TN31. It’s so long and cosy, I’m really happy with how it turned out.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I was using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git add --p&lt;/code&gt; this week and it made me wonder: “What is the hunkiest emoji”? I had a quick look and I think it might be “man playing water polo” 🤽‍ On the one hand, he’s shirtless (v hunky) on the other hand though he’s wearing a swimming cap (the antithesis of hunky).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hot or Not but for emoji?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 16:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-22</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-22</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TN31 Parka</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yahoo! Tumblr does really awful things to my photographs so I’m moving all my sewing posts over here now. Sorry if you dgaf about sewing or pictures of me wearing clothes. This post is from literally today. I’ll import the rest later. I don’t know what happens with RSS if you add really old posts. Something we can find out together. This will be the third time I’ve moved my sewing project write ups. Originally they lived on Flickr, then they went to Tumblr, now they’re here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made the &lt;a href=&quot;https://merchantandmills.com/store/patterns/the-tn31-parka/&quot;&gt;TN31 Parka from Merchant and Mills&lt;/a&gt; after seeing Nat’s mustard version and being extremely impressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cut a size 12. It has plenty of ease so still feels quite big.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fabric-and-notions&quot;&gt;Fabric and notions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The outer fabric is &lt;a href=&quot;https://merchantandmills.com/store/cloth/fern-dry-oilskin/&quot;&gt;dry oilskin in ‘Fern’&lt;/a&gt; from Merchant and Mills&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I lined it with some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.minervacrafts.com/shop/fabric/dress-fabrics/c3923-m-cotton-winceyette-flannel-dress-fabric?colour=Black&quot;&gt;black brushed cotton&lt;/a&gt; from Minerva Crafts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The neck ribbing is also from M&amp;amp;M, it’s the &lt;a href=&quot;https://merchantandmills.com/store/cloth/jansson-rib/&quot;&gt;Jansson Rib&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The buttons are &lt;a href=&quot;https://merchantandmills.com/store/trims/khaki-corozo-22mm/&quot;&gt;these ones&lt;/a&gt; from M&amp;amp;M too&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sewing-notes&quot;&gt;Sewing notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was quite a tricky sew. The lined version is basically two coats stuck together (that’s how lining works, duh). Because you can’t iron dry oilskin it’s not so easy to just iron out sloppy sewing (which is my usual trick). Dry oilskin is also very unforgiving to being unpicked as it leaves marks where the stitches were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards the end I began to struggle a lot with the volume of fabric I was trying to move about. It was quite heavy to there are a few wonky bits where I had a bit of a fight with the coat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The neck was also very difficult to sew. I’m not sure I exactly nailed it, but I really love the ribbing anyway so I can live with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What did I like about this pattern? Well, the finished item is lovely and warm. It has four pockets which is ideal for my four hands. The neckline (although I fudged it a bit) is really cute. The hidden buttons are also a really nice touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/tn31.1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;TN31&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/tn31.2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;TN31&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/tn31.3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;TN31&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/tn31.4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;TN31&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/tn31.5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;TN31&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/tn31.6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;TN31&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 09:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/tn31-parka</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/tn31-parka</guid>
        
        
        <category>sewing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weaknotes 21: IS IT APT? IS IT FUNNY? IS IT NEW?</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lukekavanagh_&quot;&gt;Luke&lt;/a&gt; showed me where to find the Financial Times style guide. I have spent hours reading it. As you would expect there is lots to enjoy. The bits about journalistic cliché’s are my favourite. Things like:
&amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;scrambling&lt;/strong&gt;
There are too many people scrambling to do something in the FT. Let them hurry if they must or even try.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The bit about apostrophes is good too:
&amp;gt; The apostrophe (‘) is not dead but it is dying. It has left Earls Court and St Andrews, but not yet Regent’s Park; and it has vanished from companies such as Barclays Bank and Currys, and magazine titles such as Farmers Weekly. […]&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This advice about puns needs to be more widely embraced:
&amp;gt;&lt;strong&gt;puns&lt;/strong&gt;
[…]
&amp;gt; It is unreasonable to expect all […] puns to be banned from the pages of the FT, particularly in features, in Weekend FT and on the Arts page. But think carefully before you commit yourself: is the pun apt? is it funny? is it new?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IS IT APT? IS IT FUNNY? IS IT NEW? Next time someone puns near me (I know who it will be, I sit near a &lt;em&gt;prolific&lt;/em&gt; punner) I’m going to say this to them.
* &lt;a href=&quot;https://natbuckley.co.uk/2019/01/20/weeknotes-1-tv-ads-and-business-models/&quot;&gt;Nat is doing weeknotes&lt;/a&gt; and they are much more interesting than mine. I’m furious!
* What is the German compound noun for when you’re upset but basically keeping it together and then somebody is nice to you and you fall into a million pieces?
* Shout out to my fellow disciples of “12-1 is the one true lunch hour”
* wooof I am very tired this week.
* I listened to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.originsthepodcast.com/&quot;&gt;the rest of this Origins podcast about Sex and The City&lt;/a&gt;. It’s put together quite poorly but some of the interviews are so good. Worth it for how cross Chris Noth is alone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 09:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-21</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-21</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weaknotes 20: Phoning in</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Weaknotes twenty!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Edith turned one year old this week. I’m considering getting a second opinion on that though, because there is no way she’s one. I can’t accept it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I started sewing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://merchantandmills.com/store/patterns/the-tn31-parka/&quot;&gt;Fern Green TN31 Parka from M&amp;amp;M&lt;/a&gt; this weekend. I realised recently that all the coats I’ve ever made have been navy blue, this is an exciting departure!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Edith started nursery this week, although she got a fever on Thursday so they sent her home. I had to look after her on Thursday and Friday which was pretty rough to be honest! Other than the sickness she has taken to nursery OK. Not too many tears.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m phoning in weaknotes this week because it’s Sunday night and I have some other things to do before I go to bed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I listened to the first episode of this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.originsthepodcast.com/&quot;&gt;Origins podcast about Sex and The City&lt;/a&gt;. It was good. I have complicated feelings about SATC. I’ve seen every episode multiple times but if you were to say to me “Alice, Sex and The City is rubbish” I’d say “you’re not wrong”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;That’s it Byeeeeeeeeee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 09:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-20</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-20</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weaknotes 19: In practice RIP my quads</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I met with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kimber_long&quot;&gt;Kimberly&lt;/a&gt;, the blog editor at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloodygoodperiod.com/&quot;&gt;Bloody Good Period&lt;/a&gt; this week. She works at the FT. She was brilliant - Bloody Good are brilliant. We’re going to team up on something menstruation related though we haven’t figured out what yet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I did some circuits at lunchtime which &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.annashipman.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Anna&lt;/a&gt; runs. In theory a great idea - exercising with nice people in a park. In practice RIP my quads.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Today we are hosting 8 (EIGHT) one year olds and their parents.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Edith started nursery this week. The only criticism I have of the nursery staff is they aren’t impressed enough by how amazing our daughter is. Like… look at her perfectly symmetrical bald head? see how good she is at climbing on the table? see how funny she is when she tries to play hide and seek? Don’t her eyes seem especially big and cute to you? Anyway. I suppose they’re just trying to be professional.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I found the Tampon Club stickers finally.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I listened to some of Matt Irvine Brown’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://musicforshuffle.com/sketches/&quot;&gt;Music for Shuffle&lt;/a&gt; again on Thursday when I was trying to focus. Still so good!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 09:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-19</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-19</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>rip Flickr</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Flickr is going to start charging for accounts and deleting photos from free accounts over 1000. I stopped using Flickr a few years ago because it seemed really likely that it was going to go down the shitter in Yahoo!’s custody.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m pleased that’s not going to happen but since I’ve stopped using it, I’m not going to start again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a look back through all my favourites and all the photos I’m tagged in. Nearly all of the ones not taken by me are from 2011-2013 when I was at BERG. Here are some of my faves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;baby-me-at-interesting-2008&quot;&gt;Baby me at Interesting 2008&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am 21 in this photo! I recall Interesting 2008 being really exciting. I made a last-minute decision to go with &lt;a href=&quot;https://rooreynolds.com&quot;&gt;Roo&lt;/a&gt; as he had a spare ticket. I was supposed to be moving house that weekend but decided to leave it until until Sunday. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/annapickard&quot;&gt;Anna Pickard&lt;/a&gt; said the word “plinth” on stage while nearly crying with laughter and then, after, I met her and she told me she always wears special shoes on stage. An event I clearly thought was important enough to remember. And look! &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamesbridle.com/&quot;&gt;James Bridle&lt;/a&gt; is in the background. I didn’t actually meet him properly until June 2010. I know the date because there is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/russss/4712449350/in/album-72157624303682296/&quot;&gt;another photo on Flickr from the last.fm bbq that I met him at&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/interesting08.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Interesting&quot; /&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/bowbrick/2599391457/in/photosof-alicebartlett/&quot;&gt;Original&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lots-of-drinking-outside-pubs&quot;&gt;Lots of drinking outside pubs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think maybe 50% of these photos are taken by &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/timoarnall&quot;&gt;Timo&lt;/a&gt; and are of BERG and BERG-adjacent people drinking outside pubs.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/tom-alice-joe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Alice, Tom and James&quot; /&gt;
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/timo/6227330642/in/photosof-alicebartlett/&quot;&gt;Original&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pizza.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pizza!&quot; /&gt;
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/timo/8280980308/in/album-72157647033256218/&quot;&gt;Original&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;doing-crosswords-at-berg&quot;&gt;Doing crosswords at BERG&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://designswarm.com/&quot;&gt;Alex D-S&lt;/a&gt; left a Guardian cryptic crossword out at the Brig and from then on we used to do them at lunchtime. Timo really hates cryptic crosswords.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/alice-denise-crossword.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Alice and Denise Wilton&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/alice-phil-crossword.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Alice and Phil Gyford&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/crossword.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Crossword at lunch&quot; /&gt;
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/timo/6477288445/in/album-72157647033256218/&quot;&gt;Originals&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/timo/6459405277/in/album-72157647033256218/&quot;&gt;are&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/timo/6918670183/in/photosof-alicebartlett/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;alice-counting-screws-quite-loudly&quot;&gt;Alice counting screws (quite loudly)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember this really clearly. God that office was grim. I was doing inventory for screws for Little Printer right next to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gyford.com&quot;&gt;Phil&lt;/a&gt;. Poor Phil.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/counting-screws.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Counting screws&quot; /&gt;
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/philgyford/11325773703/in/photosof-alicebartlett/&quot;&gt;Original by Phil here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-newcastle-when-me-and-mark-hurrell-wore-matching-outfits&quot;&gt;In Newcastle when Me and Mark Hurrell wore matching outfits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally we’ve made it past 2013. This photo was taken by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.benterrett.com/&quot;&gt;Ben Terrett&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/benterrett/12769099183/in/photosof-alicebartlett/&quot;&gt;Original with Ben’s dad’s comments is here&lt;/a&gt;. This was taken when I was at GDS. We were on a trip to Newcastle to hire for an HMRC centre up there. We did two days of Civil Service interviews in hotel rooms with the beds removed. My main memories were feeling a bit sweaty. I sewed that top myself.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/alice-mark.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Alice and Mark Hurrell&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 22:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/rip-flickr</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/rip-flickr</guid>
        
        
        <category>photos</category>
        
        <category>flickr</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weaknotes 18: Stop torturing me with your bad manicures</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Happy new year! We spent ours playing Pandemic Legacy 2.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I fell off the weaknotes wagon because I wrote a blog post about &lt;a href=&quot;http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/shared-parental-leave&quot;&gt;Shared Parental Leave&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/yearnotes-2018&quot;&gt;yearnotes&lt;/a&gt; instead. But this week I’m back baby!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I started work again on the 2nd. Hardly anybody was in so I got stuck into the emails and quick jobs that didn’t manage last year.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This month I’m going to run a workshop with my team about how to write concisely and clearly. I’ve had fun designing it - it’s given me an opportunity to dig out some favourite blog posts and style guides on writing. Just so we’re clear: there will be no mention of how to use apostrophes properly or do spelling.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We played “What became of Edith Finch” through Steam. It was good! Dark and spooky while also not too taxing. But! There is no way the lead character (Edith) has that manicure! What the hell! The Venn intersection of “Perfect french tips with square shaping” and “wears grey knitted fingerless mittens” is empty. I am happy to be a nail consultant on your next game or kickstarter product video, please just stop torturing me with your bad manicures.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/edith_finch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Edith Finch hands&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We watched Bandersnatch. I was quite bored by it tbh.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We watched LOOOOOFAAAAHHHHH. It was too scary for me. And also literally too dark? There were a few scenes that were too gloomy for me to be able to see what was going on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 10:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-18</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-18</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Yearnotes 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello! Yearnotes time again. To anyone unfamiliar, I write these at the end of every year for my own benefit mostly. They’re obviously very personal. I like reading about how other people’s years have gone, so if you’ve written some let me know!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a couple of big things that happened this year. I had a baby! We did some serious building work on our house! I changed roles at the Financial Times!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lets-get-the-baby-thing-out-of-the-way-first&quot;&gt;Let’s get the baby thing out of the way first&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edith was born in January at 3:57am weighing 8lb 11oz. She arrived after a six day long inpatient induction. In an almost dream like twist of events one of my best friends from sixth form college (with whom I had lost touch) turned up as my anaesthetist. After she was born we spent another five nights in hospital because of a suspected infection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I treasure the memories I have of her birth. I replay them and as they get further away I feel them morphing and becoming fuzzier. Luckily because the induction was so long I had some time to write some really long emails to the few people who knew I’d gone in for it. One day I’ll re-read those and remember it all again fresh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the get-go, Edith was perfect. Full of life, furious, soft. So soft. She’s now nearly one and loves climbing, hiding behind things, being chased and eating blueberries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her arrival has turned Lachie and I into very emotional people. We have the internal consistency of cottage cheese. From the moment she was born we both just turned to mush.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a year of new experiences. At each stage (the birth, being off work, going back to work) I was bracing for it to be awful and it just… wasn’t? The birth was objectively quite bad but at each stage there were lots of nice and proficient people around, and of course Lachie, so I quite enjoyed it. Then being off work with Edith turned out to be a piece of cake and very much aligned with things I already enjoy (loafing around, cuddles). Then going back to work was extremely empowering (more on this later).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lachie and I did shared parental leave, which I’ve written a &lt;a href=&quot;http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/shared-parental-leave&quot;&gt;whole other blog post about&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;house-house-house&quot;&gt;House! House! House!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the summer we spent eight weeks living at my parents house while we had some building work done on ours. We now have a much bigger kitchen and a loft conversion. Getting that done was quite tough going (especially on Lachie who still had to go to work in London). Our house is mostly back together now, and having a kitchen that fits more than two people in is really excellent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;great-content&quot;&gt;Great content&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started writing weaknotes. These are really for me to help me remember things. There is a small group of friends that I hope are interested in me personally enough to find anecdotes like “Edith did a poo as long as her whole arm” interesting. Though, on reflection, I doubt even my most loyal of friends is interested in that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also started doing Instagram videos while pushing Edith around in the pushchair. These came about because I was a bit bored on maternity leave and missed my grown-up friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk about Tampon Club for International Women’s Day when Edith was about 2 months old. Tampon Club has slowed, largely because I’ve been busy with a baby. But I really should get back to it. Write some blog posts. Send out some stickers. Bulk buy some tampons on Ali Ba Ba.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;making-things&quot;&gt;Making things&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year I didn’t get much sewing done as for most of the year I didn’t have a room to sew in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did have a very rewarding foray into screen printing and made some nice, if a little wonky, tea towels. I did this largely while Edith was napping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did quite a bit of embroidery, probably because it takes up much less space than machine sewing and is far more portable. I made a mobile for Edith’s room (a lot of which was done in hospital), a picture of a toucan (a lot of which was done while we were away over the summer) and some hanging toys for Edith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the year I bashed out two Jack Tar bags for Lachie’s brothers for Christmas. This is such a delightful pattern I’ll probably make it many more times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipNUdo7hMjZj83UHML7J51-nnhMMPSFEVVlAloUXDzHzIXvEhbOeOrHa0SAShGrCcw?key=Y2I0NjIzTlNvRllXVGtVWGthajFpOWJyczVab0FR&quot;&gt;There is a google photos album of things I made here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-job&quot;&gt;New job&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In October I went back to work after about 10 months away for having and looking after Edith. When I went back to work I took on a new role as Principal Engineer in the Customer Products team (that’s the team that looks after FT.com and the apps). I had been leading the Origami team for a while and I was worried I’d be bored when I went back so I wanted a new challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new role has been very enjoyable so far. Having a baby has changed my approach to work as it has left me much more focussed. Because I have to leave on time I don’t faff around as much as I used to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a new manager, Anna Shipman. Being managed by Anna is pretty amazing to be honest. She strives to be the best she can be at all times and it forces me to try my hardest too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pics&quot;&gt;Pics!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual I’ve made a photo album of the best things from 2018, but it doesn’t include any photos of Edith (except one of the back of her head) because we’re keeping her off the big old internet for now. Obviously she was a huge part of my year and also extremely cute, but unless we’re friends on Instagram you’ll just have to take my word for it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://photos.app.goo.gl/Smv8fmmzr6XjwBBQ9&quot;&gt;The album is here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 21:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/yearnotes-2018</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/yearnotes-2018</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
        <category>yearnotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Shared parental leave</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This year we had a daughter and my husband and I decided to make use of Shared Parental Leave (SPL). This legislation, brought in in 2014, allows two people (in our case the mother and father, but it could be two fathers, adoptive parents, whatever) to share one year’s leave between them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In February the Department for Business said that the uptake of SPL could be as low as 2% of the 285,000 couples that are eligible for it each year. I think SPL is amazing so I thought I’d write down what we did and why it was good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog post I’m going to talk about what my husband and I did.  I’m an a heterosexual relationship but the policy I’m talking about is available to same sex (or queer!) couples and couples adopting. In these cases there is a “Primary” and a “Secondary” parent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;before-spl-things-were-bad&quot;&gt;Before SPL, things were bad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before Shared Parental Leave, I would have been entitled to a full year off work (paid at whatever my employer’s leave policy is plus statutory). My husband would have been entitled to 2 weeks off work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This situation is a bit shit for everyone. Dads (or secondaries!) get less time with their babies. Mums (or primaries!) get less support from their partners. Women have to take a disproportionate career hit. Even in families where the dads want to pitch in equally, they’re not able to because they have to be back at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;with-shared-parental-leave-you-share-your-parental-leave&quot;&gt;With Shared Parental Leave you share your parental leave&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I AM NOT A HUMAN RESOURCES PROFESSIONAL&lt;/strong&gt; so here is the explanation from &lt;a href=&quot;https://sharedparentalleave.campaign.gov.uk/&quot;&gt;https://sharedparentalleave.campaign.gov.uk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Parents can share up to 50 weeks of leave and up to 37 weeks of pay and choose to take the leave and pay in a more flexible way (each parent can take up to 3 blocks of leave, more if their employer allows, interspersed with periods of work).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Eligible parents can be off work together for up to 6 months or alternatively stagger their leave and pay so that one of them is always at home with their baby in the first year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I found confusing to begin with was understanding the pay for shared parental leave. This is because initially I thought pay was moveable (eg I get 19 weeks full pay which I can take at any time). But actually all parental pay works by providing a rate for a specific week calculated from the when the first leave is taken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if I’m off during week 13, I’ll get the week 13 rate (which in my case because of the FT’s enhanced maternity policy, is full pay). If I’m off during week 20 I’ll get statutory pay (£145.18). It doesn’t matter if week 20 is my first week off, the pay for week 20 is the statutory allowance as my employer’s enhanced pay policy ends on week 19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My parental pay is calculated based on my employer’s policy, and my partner’s parental pay rate is calculated based on his employers policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-we-took-four-weeks-off-together&quot;&gt;First we took four weeks off together&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, enough with the poorly described legislation. What did my partner and I actually &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My partner’s employer (Microsoft) gives six week’s paid paternity leave in the UK, and he could take it in up two chunks. The Financial Times’s policy is the same for everybody (mothers, fathers, primaries, secondaries, etc). We all get 19 weeks leave fully paid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we took four weeks off together. I have no idea what we did during this time - it’s a total blur. I dimly recall lots of sleeping in? And some stumbling around? And cuddles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then my husband went back to work, and for seven and a half months I was the primary parent. I also took sole responsibility for all the cooking which allowed my partner to focus on work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;being-the-primary-parent-is-hard&quot;&gt;Being the primary parent is hard!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people don’t like the phrase “primary” parent. “It minimises the other parent’s role!”. Yes it does. But look. Having been both the primary and the secondary - the primary is different and a lot harder! At all times I had to be considering the needs of quite a needy small person. She can’t tell me if she’s hungry or tired or needs a nappy change. I have to remember if she’s poorly, if she’s currently refusing broccoli, what her favourite toys are, when she last pooed. Every day has to be, at a minimum, planned so that she’ll get some baby safe food and some time for naps. Sometimes it takes her an hour to eat a whole meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The secondary parent is still important. In the evenings being able to hand over responsibility, even just for the half hour before bed, was lovely. After a day of singing and chasing and tickling and playing and cleaning and feeding, I could have some quiet time to cook dinner. I didn’t especially like cooking until it came at the end of a day’s free play with a baby. Being able to follow a set of instructions uninterrupted and at the end have some delicious food became a real treat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;switching-roles&quot;&gt;Switching roles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite being a fairly equitable pair, while I was on leave, I was the the person who was leading decisions about our daughter. Even when my partner was there too, I was in charge. This was because I knew what she needed because I was pretty much always with her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we switched I realised how much I had become accustomed to looking after a baby. How rolling with the unpredictability of a child had become how I went about the day. Seeing my partner get to grips with this challenge made me realise what a shift it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going back to work at nine months was pretty easy, especially as I knew our daughter was with her dad. We chose a nine/three split because I wanted my partner to have a good chunk of time to get into being the primary. It took him a while to settle into the role so I’m glad we picked three months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose to express milk at work for three months when I went back. This was an awful experience to be honest. I’m somewhat on the fence about if I would recommend doing that to anyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tips-for-anyone-wanting-to-take-spl&quot;&gt;Tips for anyone wanting to take SPL&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engage your HR rep. My contact in the FT’s HR team described SPL as the most complicated piece of legislation they have to deal with. There are a huge number of ways to take SPL so talking through them with an expert is a really good idea.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try and have it so you both have some solo time. I gained so much empathy for what it was like being the secondary parent when I had to do it, and I know my husband learnt heaps from being the primary. Our daughter also got a lot from having a different parent running the show.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get yourself a spreadsheet. Organising maternity leave, paternity leave, shared parental leave, the annual leave you will still accrue while being on leave, all across multiple financial years is a logistical nightmare. I’m not going to share my spreadsheet because I think it probably only makes sense to me, but it was essential in working out what I was going to be paid, when I should return to work, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK - that’s it. I hope more people will take Shared Parental Leave. I must state again that &lt;strong&gt;I AM NOT A HUMAN RESOURCES PROFESSIONAL&lt;/strong&gt;, but if you have any questions about what we did that I haven’t covered here, just pop me an &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#105;&amp;#099;&amp;#101;&amp;#046;&amp;#098;&amp;#097;&amp;#114;&amp;#116;&amp;#108;&amp;#101;&amp;#116;&amp;#116;&amp;#064;&amp;#103;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 10:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/shared-parental-leave</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/shared-parental-leave</guid>
        
        
        <category>shared-parental-leave</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weaknotes 17: Minimum Viable Parenting</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lachie and I have caught some kind of stomach bug so spent the last few days either in bed or doing Minimum Viable Parenting on our daughter as we try not to barf. Rice cakes and grapes for dinner again darling! As luck would have it we are currently surrounded by family members who are all pitching in too.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My &lt;a href=&quot;http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/five-facts-about-smell&quot;&gt;post about smell&lt;/a&gt; has been put on Hacker News, which explains why about seven new people started following me on Twitter and why I got two emails about that post despite it being from 2014. Hello if you’re reading this from Hacker News. Though I’m too much of a chicken to go and read what people are saying about the post (what if someone is being mean to me on the internet!?!), I’ve seen some very flattering comments so thank you if you’re being nice about me.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I really want to know who is flying drones over Gatwick. At first I thought it was going to turn out to be some green activists like Extinction Rebellion but they have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2018/dec/20/tens-of-thousands-of-passengers-stranded-by-gatwick-airport-drones&quot;&gt;denied involvement&lt;/a&gt;. Now maybe it turns out there were no drones at all, which is entirely plausible to me, having listened to that Malcolm Gladwell podcast about  &lt;a href=&quot;http://revisionisthistory.com/episodes/28-the-imaginary-crimes-of-margit-hamosh&quot;&gt;collective hysterias&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[More about podcasts] I finished listening to the second series of &lt;a href=&quot;https://slate.com/slow-burn&quot;&gt;Slow Burn&lt;/a&gt;. This series is about the Clinton impeachment. This was much more gripping than the Nixon one somehow. I think maybe it was easier to follow. I keep trying to sum up what I think about Clinton having listened to this podcast but having tried a few takes none of them are very good so I’m just going to leave it at Clinton: a horrible man.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;[Podcasts] On a car journey Lachie and I listened to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://99percentinvisible.org/episode/the-accidental-room/&quot;&gt;99% invisible episode about… a room in a mall?&lt;/a&gt;. The best I can summarise it is some people find a secret void in a mall which you have to get to by going through a series of weird gaps in between designed spaces. They manage to fill it with furniture and then they live in it. Not full time, but they spend days in it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 11:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-17</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://alicebartlett.co.uk/blog/weaknotes-17</guid>
        
        
        <category>weaknotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
